Krish NAik: Everybody, good morning.
Krish NAik: We could just check the chats are opened or not.
Krish NAik: Tricky, I have power issues. That's why, like,
Krish NAik: I don't know what happened, like, for the past 10 minutes, the cycle backup is also not coming.
Krish NAik: So all my other systems are actually down.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'll be taking a few chats, so let's wait for 5 minutes, and then we'll be starting the session.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we have winter storm in USA. Alright, chat is working already, if we can read this. Yes, I can do that, MS,
Krish NAik: Jim, good morning.
Krish NAik: Hmm, alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, fine, from here till… alright, guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, Amanda was for projects, 40+, I think he has released. Do we need to pay again? That's a different… that's a different subscription. That's not a course. That's a bundle of projects, Amand.
Krish NAik: So generally, I suggest students who have time, okay, or any specific project, if you are interested in, then you can get it. There you can get, actually, project with respect to Azure, Database, the things that we don't discuss.
Krish NAik: Because that's another mentor who actually takes it. Yes, like, it has the recorded version. Okay, it means that directly you'll be getting the videos, as there are more than 40 projects there.
Krish NAik: Like, every week, like, two classes, I think, at night that they are planning, from 8pm to 10pm, or something like that, okay, they will be discussing, projects. It means I can walk through and high-level understanding.
Krish NAik: Because, just think about, like, for example, like, yesterday's project, if I'm talking about, okay, for me, it's not possible to complete in 2 days. It might take more time. Okay, so it will be much more than work through. They won't teach you the technology, rather than using the tech they will teach you.
Krish NAik: Okay? So it's not about covering, so you should always have the prerequisites. If you have that, then you can take that project monthly.
Krish NAik: That is already launched, please check, I think, because the exact name, I'm not sure.
Krish NAik: I don't know, like, just wait hard to do a few changes with respect to my setup.
Krish NAik: I fixed the deployment issue, okay, I think,
Krish NAik: Backup game, just wait one minute.
Krish NAik: Letting me attach again all the…
Krish NAik: No, good.
Krish NAik: Alright, so I think we are good now. Screen, this is desktop 2.
Krish NAik: Let me just return.
Krish NAik: Anyways, let's move on this.
Krish NAik: I missed yesterday's class. If you have missed yesterday's class, nothing I can do, you can later on go through the recording.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Hmm… Janika… I use an extension, Janika, okay? So, for example, if you check my extensions, I think…
Krish NAik: Okay, are you having…
Krish NAik: some extension with respect to the markdown one. Okay, this markdown preview announced. Because of that, I can see the…
Krish NAik: deployment files, MD files.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can install this particular extension, whoever is asking with respect to that.
Krish NAik: Alright, today, no, no, no, not a new project. Say, our, project part, I will just give you a quick pathway, like, what are the things. Today, we'll be discussing the code part, okay? And, like, today, I have kept this deployment talk, okay? So, let me just open the guitar.
Krish NAik: people, if you want to do it by yourself, you can do it step-by-step. I've kept everything, but later on, I think that I will be discussing next week one.
Krish NAik: Not today. So today, just a simple quote walkthrough. The idea is, take your time this week, go through, because too much
Krish NAik: the codebase is really big as compared to other projects that I have, discussed in other batches also, so…
Krish NAik: Which one is the heaviest open?
Krish NAik: Even I slept 3-4 hours old. I was working on the deployment, I have fixed it, because ERM64, I have removed it, with the current support of x86 that I told. Okay, so now everything, and if you check, the deployment is pretty much success, and I have tested it also.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, inside the… I think, okay, that folder, I have not posted, looks like. Fine.
Krish NAik: Just create extensions, yes.
Krish NAik: Docs, okay, yes. This is the Mountdown file, actually, okay?
Krish NAik: So, in this Markdown file, all the steps with respect to the deployment, because a few minor changes that I did, previously I was working with, API Gateway. As you know, that API Gateway has a pretty much hard limit of 29 seconds, so when I was actually working with, bigger documents.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, I was facing the problem to get the response if it was taking more than 29 seconds. So I actually switched back to function environments, directly on top of LandApp. Okay, it's completely free to use, so only that change that I have
Krish NAik: Should we take a pull? You can take a poll, because if you look into my comments…
Krish NAik: So, just okay with that.
Krish NAik: If you look into my commits, a few commits I have done, based on the new, I think last one, AWS variables and migration from AWS account, okay? So, yes, you can take a commit to, just do a git pull, you will get the recent one.
Krish NAik: I have not used Markdown or that extension. Later on, I will check it out.
Krish NAik: We need the name of that same extension.
Krish NAik: I should know right now, whoever needs that. I am using a widget suggested Markdown, all that also you can taste. My one is Markdown Preview Enhanced.
Krish NAik: This is the name.
Krish NAik: Okay, so markdown preview announced.
Krish NAik: So here, all the steps and everything that I've written from scratch, step by step, so anybody can do it. But, this, deployment discussion, I'll be doing it, next week, not today. Today, let's go through the codebase ones, then take your time.
Krish NAik: And next week, I'll be doing the deployment.
Krish NAik: Because for deployment also, I need close to, like, more than 2 hours. A lot of steps are there, but at least I've removed that API gateway, because of that, at least the steps are lessened.
Krish NAik: I will just show you the deployment architecture, so that at least next week I don't need to discuss the architecture for the deployment.
Krish NAik: Okay, have I pushed that? Okay, I have not added that, just wait.
Krish NAik: Definitely.
Krish NAik: No, no, I don't use a paid account. Everything is open source.
Krish NAik: It might take some time to render, I think it's better to open it in the local.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Yes, Rahul, career. It will be in the paused mode, you can resume it. I think they take it if there is no activity for 7 days or something like that. They pause it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's start with our deployment architecture, and then we will be talking about the codeables.
Krish NAik: So, only this file that I have added, okay, a new workflow, so you guys also can check directly from the workflow folder.
Krish NAik: So, the first one is the CICD pipeline, a very similar approach, I am using GitHub Actions. Okay.
Krish NAik: And once you push it to your GitHub repository, the main branch will be detected if there is any change or not.
Krish NAik: As you can see here. Okay, and now, a few other things. First of all, we will check out the code, then we will set up QEMU. Okay, now this QEMU part…
Krish NAik: I'm planning to remove it, because it is not really required if you are working with x86 and 64 architectures. So generally, for ARM64 architectures, you need this step.
Krish NAik: Okay? But again, like, it doesn't create a lot of problem. Inside this, also, you can do that, I can say, because this is an email, okay? Like, any type of… How many of you know about key UVMU?
Krish NAik: Yes, you, you…
Krish NAik: No, no, just with it, because really, yes.
Krish NAik: They're too niche.
Krish NAik: If you are working with CI-CT, then only you will understand.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is really a big one.
Krish NAik: Okay, as you can see, this is an evaluator and a virtualizer, which gives you the support to execute ARM-based images. If you're working with… generally, I prefer working with ARM-based images. Why? They are cheaper.
Krish NAik: Close to 20 to 30% cheaper, they have faster builds.
Krish NAik: the simplest example, if you think about, like, Mac systems and Windows systems.
Krish NAik: Okay, every Mac is based on ER after 2021.
Krish NAik: So I feel that ARM images are cheaper, they are, they are faster also, with respect to the Docker build and everything. So, generally, I prefer working with this particular
Krish NAik: emulator and virtualizer, if you are working with them. But I have not changed that particular step. It means that it supports both, but highly specialized for ERM64.
Krish NAik: First time, okay, few people who have done it previously. Now, inside this emulator, we'll be doing, we'll be doing our Docker build.
Krish NAik: then the AWS credentials, so all these credentials from where we'll be getting it?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me in the last project also you have done, from where you will be getting your AWS credentials.
Krish NAik: So, if I show you my credentials… Yeah.
Krish NAik: Prompt GitHub Secrets, correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, just reap,
Krish NAik: Text2SQL… Okay, so right now you can see the… because I've done a new commit, so yes, the deployment will start.
Krish NAik: But I will quickly… okay, not security, sorry.
Krish NAik: I have to go to…
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the other account, that's why I cannot get that setting page, just wait.
Krish NAik: Settings… all those things that you have in the E&V, you need to pass it here, so…
Krish NAik: Actions, and let me show you.
Krish NAik: Actually, you don't need this API Gateway URL anymore, but other than that, AWS access key ID, AWS account ID secret, database URL, OpenAI API key, OPEC API key, Pinecone, Pinecone environment, Pinecone index name.
Krish NAik: S3 bucket name, so in my case, my variable name is S3CatcherBucket, but it's the actual bucket that you create the name. And then you have the abstash credentials, the Redis token, and the UR. Okay, so these are all the repo secrets that I have kept for the deployment.
Krish NAik: So, from here, it will be pulled.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once the credentials are verified, then in the next step, you have login to ECR. Why? Because the Docker build is done, so you need to push that image to ECR.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, log in to ECR, build, then tagging the image with AMD64, and this particular… now, the AWS infra comes. So here, to your ECR Docker registry, in a private registry will be pushing the image.
Krish NAik: And from there, Lambda will use that particular image. So in Lambda, I've given the settings of 3GB RAM, and the timeout is 15 minutes.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I know majorly, like, 15 minutes is really, like, a good one. You don't need to change anything. Now, getting the public endpoint. For that, I am working with, now, function URLs. Okay? Because I told you what is the problem with API Gateway?
Krish NAik: there is a hard limit of 29 seconds, so anything more than 29 seconds. It means that you can show it in the background that something is processing.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the response, you can do something like that.
Krish NAik: Okay, otherwise, you can switch to Lambda functions, because API Gateway comes always with an extra added, price. So I thought about, let's keep it simple, and I have removed that particular service and kept only the Lambda function, URL.
Krish NAik: Yes, today is pretty much the code walkthrough.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… then… right now, I don't have any type of integration test, just I have kept it as a dummy. Okay, because, I don't know, like, you have the Moto package, similarly, you can replicate any test with the Moto package. How many of you know about the Moto package?
Krish NAik: in AWS.
Krish NAik: to… to do replicated tests. Yes, anybody has used the…
Krish NAik: Motomyta are basically a mocking of moto.
Krish NAik: Not a simulator, I'm talking about the package belt. Okay, Jatindar, okay, if you think about, yes, I'm walking simulator, if you think about… correct.
Krish NAik: Okay, now if the tests are passed, the deployment is success, and finally you will be getting notified. So, this is the high-level architecture for now, I've kept.
Krish NAik: Now, coming to the next step, much more with respect to your application part. Now, yesterday I told you, whenever you are working with AWS Lambda, you need an adapter. So, in our case, I told you the name of the packages. What is the name of the package?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me, yesterday I told.
Krish NAik: what is the name of the package, okay? Amit remembers, Aniruz remembers. Few people are telling Bhutto, Bhutto is not the correct answer.
Krish NAik: At least look into the image that I am sharing, okay? Magnum is the name, okay?
Krish NAik: Ice cream name, just remember, I think. You have an ice cream name, I think? Based on that magnum. Yes, so…
Krish NAik: This is the package. Okay, now, through this package, like, Magnum, why very specifically? Because I'm working with FastAPI. So, generally, it has support with respect to FastAPI, but directly I can say for every route, okay, when to start an event, when to close an event, so all the support that I get.
Krish NAik: So…
Krish NAik: This is the client layer, and this is the function URL. So let me just show you in the UI exactly how it will look like, because otherwise you might feel that
Krish NAik: exactly how the functioning URL looks like, AWTS, let's move this over.
Krish NAik: Alright, I'm already logged in. I didn't call the app done.
Krish NAik: Alright, so this is the function that I have created.
Krish NAik: Okay, and, so… This particular function is using this Docker image that I have pushed.
Krish NAik: In the ECR, so from ECR that it's getting. And later on, I have done this, so… right now, the build is going on, so open link in new tab, let me see that. Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can see that you will be getting this. So, now this URL generation, how I've done? Directly, functions URL are available inside Lambda. How many of you know about function URLs? Please let me know.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: If you don't know… Right?
Krish NAik: Generally, under the configuration part.
Krish NAik: you can look into, like, what are the environment variables that I'm using. Okay, so just, I'm showing you internal Lambda configurations. So, see, right now I'm exposing all my keys, but guys,
Krish NAik: you can see all those things in detail. So, during the deployment, so I'll be passing a command through which I'll be updating all this environment.
Krish NAik: variables that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and here you have this function URL.
Krish NAik: It will take, the first time to load.
Krish NAik: Okay, so way strong is through this, I can make it public.
Krish NAik: Just, remember, whenever you are working with, functioning URLs, two separate permissions are required, the lambda invoke function and the lambda invoke functioning URL. Okay, so…
Krish NAik: this particular policy needs to be added, because it got updated in, I think, 2025 last, or in 2026 starting. Few changes were there.
Krish NAik: As I looked into.
Krish NAik: Yes, we do need the API Gateway, because API Gateway, I told you what is the main problem, how much, okay, that 29-second heart limit. Actually, I was testing with a bigger PDF, then I felt that let's remove that component and make it simple.
Krish NAik: Now, Navodesh Sharma is telling without lambda also can be done. Now, you cannot create function URLs without lambda.
Krish NAik: you need lambda, then only you can create that function URL. Okay?
Krish NAik: It's like Azure Functions, yes, yes, yes, pretty much.
Krish NAik: In Google, also, you have
Krish NAik: functions, I think. What is the exact name of the package? I think in Google also. So, very similar. Functions and Lambda that you have. All are serverless.
Krish NAik: And that is the cheapest option that you can… yes, Cloud Function is the name in JCP Connect.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, through function URL, I actually generated this particular URL, and through this, you can access the application.
Krish NAik: So, alright. How do… see, if it's a step-by-step, you can easily remember it. It's not really complex right now. I feel that it's easy, because…
Krish NAik: When you actually work in prod, then other things also comes. The AI part is always easy to remember, as compared to your entire SG part.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, so first of all, this is my client layer, that is basically the fast API part. With that, I'll be accessing it through the Lambda function URL, so whatever that public endpoint that you'll be getting.
Krish NAik: It will invoke our main Lambda function, which is the RAT Text2SQL Serverless, so this is the name of my Lambda function. Now, this Lambda function will first invoke our Magnum adapter, okay, through which I'll be accessing the
Krish NAik: fast API application, okay? And this Lambda function will also have access to S3 bucket. Now, these are all AWS-related services, I'm not talking
Krish NAik: about other services, like buying one another, because those services will be handled directly via Fast API, okay? So that's why S3 bucket catching, and why I have done it.
Krish NAik: Because if you are uploading any document in AWS, so first I was actually saving it in the local, if you remember, slash 10.
Krish NAik: So, if I show you my function variables…
Krish NAik: Okay, so by default, you can see, like, I've defined, like, for this temp. So first, I used to save inside that lambda environment, then I used to push it in a
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, very specifically, I can say that lambda was connected with S3. So first, I save it, then I push it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now…
Krish NAik: Okay, so through Magnum, I'm accessing the Fast API, and then Fast API part you guys already know, so majorly all the responses that I'll be getting.
Krish NAik: through our main JSON response, and then comes your main hybrid routing service, the query routing. Through that, the document query, your PineCon vector database, so this is the part with retriever. Then, the embedding creation.
Krish NAik: Then you have the LLM access, so majorly, all these are under the RAG service, okay? So, if I show you in the source code… so, source code, source code, where is traya, traya, traya, traya.
Krish NAik: Okay, no, actually, it was opened only.
Krish NAik: So, if you look into the app folder, APB,
Krish NAik: Inside the app folder, you will be having the app service.
Krish NAik: Sorry, rag service. So, now this is the main service through which all the connections are done. So, I'm not using any Lama Index or Landshake. Last class also I've told, so don't get confused how I'm doing.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I want to just discuss and workflow, because even I don't prefer using Llama and Langshan, because they always come with a big size and a lot of bundle packages.
Krish NAik: So, for beginners, that is good. Later on, you can make things much more independent.
Krish NAik: Okay, so we'll adjust it.
Krish NAik: Redis is a third party, so directly connected with Fast API is not with LAM Matesh. Okay, so I'm not kept on Redis. Rather than the Fast API, application will be doing that access.
Krish NAik: Alright, so that's why all these external services, like Supabase, Pine Bones.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in Pinecone, if you remember, so I created two.
Krish NAik: In Texas, one for your saving the chunks, and the other was for the VANA part. Because till now, I've not discussed the VANA sequel training.
Krish NAik: Okay, but next week, I'll be doing that.
Krish NAik: Then comes your OpenAI LLM generation called… okay, because even for SQL service, for VANA, that particular LLM configuration, I was using GPT-4, I think.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally come here,
Krish NAik: Upstage Redis, because for everything through Redis data, I'll be making the connection. So if you look into my RAG service is also connected to Redis, even my SQL service is also connected to Redis, even my hybrid query, where, like, in both the places I send the query, in that. Everything is connected to my Redis.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, these are some estimated costs through AI that has been generated. Okay, now,
Krish NAik: This is, I think,
Krish NAik: Yes, here, in Lambda, the timeout that I've taken is 15 minutes, so I think that 15 minutes is more than enough.
Krish NAik: for any type of bigger document also that you can process. Because I had one option to use API Gateway by, adding to asynchronous process, but again, I feel that,
Krish NAik: If I keep it in backend, if I show just the response that, yes, it is processing, please check after a few minutes.
Krish NAik: I can do that also, that option was there with me, but I thought about it's better to get a response where at least you can see the number of chunks and other things.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that option also, you can use it, but I thought about, again, an added, service with more charge that comes.
Krish NAik: So I have removed that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is the poor Lambda configuration that I have with 10GB of storage, because clearly I'm not saving anything.
Krish NAik: Because anything… the documents that you are uploading, I'm pushing them to S3. So, really, like, I can keep it 10GB. My core application takes less than that, only the environment. I think it takes around 3GB in total.
Krish NAik: Okay, so odd type, right now my function URN will be pretty much public access.
Krish NAik: course, allow all regions, these are a few of the permissions according to 2026, because previously I've done… there it was not required, but in 2026, I felt that these two are pretty much
Krish NAik: required, then only you can use the function URL for public access.
Krish NAik: Okay, then the Docker image, the environment variables, this I've already told you, okay? And then, if you want to do a curl operation, so for that, I have used it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few monitoring commands, and the final deployment command.
Krish NAik: Then, high level, this will be the main core flow.
Krish NAik: I think for everybody, if you have any questions, you can ask me.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, we will start our main discussion.
Krish NAik: Right now, all 2.0 token authentication, right now, few things, but not a lot of things that can be done.
Krish NAik: Redis will store SQL catcher, but Rack Catchave will be in S3.
Krish NAik: Yesterday, I discussed these things. Your document catcher, and your query response catcher, that will be in practice. Whether for SQL, weather for RAM.
Krish NAik: Okay, Matesh?
Krish NAik: Both the things.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will come to that. Till now, I'm not written. I have just opened my notepad. I will come to that.
Krish NAik: a B-shake, it's a… it's for mocking Boto.
Krish NAik: related testing things. For that, you can use Moto.
Krish NAik: Just wait. Let me now tell you, because whenever you are building a rack, even I will suggest that if you have a very specific requirement, and if you are not getting in any packages.
Krish NAik: then actually, it's better to go with Lang Channel Lama Enterprise. I feel majorly now, there are individual packages which are much more lighter and better for integrations.
Krish NAik: So, let me just open my notepad.
Krish NAik: Rag, okay, just straight, let me clicked.
Krish NAik: Now I will start sharing my notes.
Krish NAik: I will stop sharing the screen, and let's get into it.
Krish NAik: iPad wire cable.
Krish NAik: Alright, so here…
Krish NAik: So, whenever you are building a rag, okay, the idea is to keep your main package much more lightweight, so, like, llama Index.
Krish NAik: And… Line chain or haystack.
Krish NAik: you can simply remove those components. Why? So, first of all, if I am simple… simply telling about data parcel.
Krish NAik: This is the first step.
Krish NAik: For data parsing, what are the libraries that you can use? Because we have already gone through this, so tell me in the chat quickly.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you can use Undockly, you can use Unstructured, anything. Llama parts also have discussed, okay, PDF Miner, PiMu PDF, so many things are there. Okay, so those libraries.
Krish NAik: separate libraries for now. In our project, we are working, so I will just write DocLink.
Krish NAik: In this project, even we have support for unstructured hours.
Krish NAik: Now, after passing, what is the next step?
Krish NAik: Janika… Lanchen, don't tell me. So right now, whatever the discussion I'm doing, I'm not doing with the prospect of Lanshan or Lam.
Krish NAik: The next step is pretty much chunking.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, for chunking, you can use something like chunky, Okay, you can use Docklink.
Krish NAik: Okay, and there are, like, for… if you are working with, semantic chunking, there is a specific code as, same chunk. Okay, there are many libraries which are available, so it's not necessary. You always, go with the landing, or the Lama index available.
Krish NAik: Okay, so it's really not required.
Krish NAik: So, once the chunks are ready, the next step is embedding.
Krish NAik: for embedding directly whichever LLM call that you are making. Okay, so for example, through OpenAI,
Krish NAik: You can do it.
Krish NAik: were anthropic.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Or even, like, through OLAMA, so everywhere. It means that the dependency of Langchen and Llama Index is not there. Once the embeddings are done, then in the next step, you have the vector stored.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, this is the part where I feel it gets interesting, because through the vector store package, for sure, you will be able to create the collection.
Krish NAik: After the collection is created, you can push your vectors in that particular collection. So, for example, in our case, right now, I'm using Pinecone. So, you have to install that Pinecone package, and through that package, you can send your vectors. Now, every vector store, previously, I've told it many times, they provide you the retrieval
Krish NAik: Okay, so the retrieval operation.
Krish NAik: For that, you can use the same vector store package.
Krish NAik: Everyone supports it, whether you are working with VV8, Milvas, Quadrant, everywhere.
Krish NAik: Okay? Once your retrieval is done.
Krish NAik: Then what is the next step?
Krish NAik: You got your top kitchen from here.
Krish NAik: You know that you have to do a formatting.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if you remember that, we used to create a dev format, okay, through which we used to perform a join operation on top of this topK chance.
Krish NAik: Okay, so right now I'm just passing it as a parameter, pseudocode. Okay.
Krish NAik: I have to create that, and then I have to send it to the LLM?
Krish NAik: with any specific instructions that I want to pass it.
Krish NAik: That's the only thing, so that I can directly do it using that, again, the OpenAI package.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why directly I can call it through OpenAI, so you really don't need…
Krish NAik: Okay, so for your final response generation.
Krish NAik: In the response generation, so it means that, first of all, you will be passing the query. So that query, you need to embed it
Krish NAik: So that embedding also can be done through this particular package of OpenAI, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no, because in Langchen and Lama Index, you know that, behind the scenes, it does it. But when you manually do the implementation, you have to take care of that embedding. Okay, so during your response generation, you'll be getting that query. Okay, so query…
Krish NAik: And then comes the context.
Krish NAik: that I have created.
Krish NAik: Okay, down this, you have to create the embedding.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you have the embedding, then only you can perform the retrieval, okay? So, I should have written it in this step, but I hope everyone gets that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is through here, for the retrieval part.
Krish NAik: And finally, once you have the final query with the context, if you want to add some more information, just like your prompt, you can pass it as a string, okay? And then finally, you can send. So it's pretty much… there is no dependency of Langchen or Llama Index, or HSTAC.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you, that I feel that this is a much more lighter implementation that I feel.
Krish NAik: The clarity is much better. You have much more power.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the only dependency that I feel that, with respect to this, embedding packages, because they also get updated like LanChain. But the updates are much more stable updates as compared to Langchain or Lama Intex.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why there is no dependency of Llama, or LandChain, or Haystack, anything that I'll be discussing in future. Those are high-level frameworks. So generally, for beginners, if you want to write less amount of code, that's your best fit.
Krish NAik: But if you want much more power.
Krish NAik: Okay, try to go with everything custom.
Krish NAik: Then you can actually do, for example.
Krish NAik: if I want to build my new package, or some type of service, and if I want to do the integration with Landshain. Okay, so what happens? I feel that every time there is a dependency, it means that I know that, okay, my entire source code is in Lanschain. Now, if I want to just attach one functionality.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I have to do, actually, a lot of changes, just because of Langchain support. It means that the framework that I'm building, it should have the support with Langchain, or with Llama, or with Haystack. So generally, for developers, like, if I'm talking, adoption becomes much easier, because I know everybody in the community is using Langchain.
Krish NAik: So, I need to provide those support also, but just if I don't want to share the package with anyone. So, do you really think I need to provide a support for Langshan? I can focus on my core functionality.
Krish NAik: In my development, rather than thinking about
Krish NAik: If I'm making it as a community package, then it's a different story, but actual for my core purpose of building or developing a certain service.
Krish NAik: That's why I feel that it's not a good thing, always to work with Lanshan. That's why in this project, I have not used anywhere. And I think everybody knows that with LanChain, if you are installing, how many packages gets installed?
Krish NAik: Or with Llama Intense. It's not a single package. With that, more than, again, 15-20 packages that comes.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: That's why I'm telling you. So, whenever you are building, it's much more better, you have much more power.
Krish NAik: Because this embedding and vector store operations are highly optimized.
Krish NAik: Rather than going through that, I can say langchain wrapper. Whenever you are working with a wrapper, always remember.
Krish NAik: one or two millisecond drop will be there. I think everybody agrees on that. Whenever you are working with any high-level wrappers.
Krish NAik: At least 1 or 2 milliseconds, that is the bare minimum I have taken. It might be more.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's what I'm telling you. Please try to go through this operation rather than that. That was the main purpose of telling you, because you guys already know the life tricks.
Krish NAik: Even in LanChain, if you're working with, separately, it will ask you to install LangChain, Pinecode package.
Krish NAik: Okay, and even with that, the own Pinecone package also. I think you guys remember, you have done the installation of languages quadrant package. With that, again, you installed Quadrant Client.
Krish NAik: Because all the functionalities of the core quadrant vector databases are not even available in LandChain Quadrant. Then what is the purpose of using it?
Krish NAik: I hope everybody's getting, like, what's the idea that I'm telling you.
Krish NAik: Okay, so when you were building your solution, remember. So, Langshan and LamanTech is developer-friendly, but when you know the internal thing.
Krish NAik: So, I don't feel it is a requirement.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is much more modular design, you can always plug and click. It means that if you're building a certain service for one client, the same things you can quickly put together. Okay, probably with respect to embedding, if the client has a different requirement, okay, you can simply change this.
Krish NAik: So, much more powerful, much more controllable, you get better speeds. The whole level of optimizations that can be done with respect to embeddings, because, again, for vector TV or embedding optimizations, you have to use the core package. You cannot do it through LANG.
Krish NAik: Okay, so…
Krish NAik: Will this custom part work with Langrapp? Yes, Sank. See, any agent framework, I treat agent as pretty much simple functions, and nothing much more. When you execute a function, you get something.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, in every agentic framework, you can work with custom tools.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay. Now, within that custom tool, I can keep these functions.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for developers, I'm telling, like, start with if you don't know nothing about RAM, then Lama Index is fine, or Langchain is fine. But if you know the internal things, not right.
Krish NAik: Even, like, for example, the hybrid Retriever implementation, if I want to do it. I know that every major VectorTV package has that.
Krish NAik: then why you need to land it?
Krish NAik: Okay, it means that it can directly support your BM25 such. Probably, like, your split is not available. Now you have to check, because in Milverse, I showed you Splate was available. How many of you remember?
Krish NAik: So now, the availability of split can be one thing. So, there you might need to bring, okay, a custom one I am bringing, so we need to check that, okay, Quadrant directly supports Splate or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's the only thing. It means that some functionality can be during, user-specific, so that is available directly with the vector DB. Please have a checkmark.
Krish NAik: Rather than directly be dependent on your major frameworks.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, simple example in deep learning, most of you know about PyTorch, but any high-level frameworks which is built on top of PyTorch, anybody has used.
Krish NAik: like, lightning.
Krish NAik: Yes, anybody who's used Lightning?
Krish NAik: Lightning, PyTorch, Lightning is the name of the package. It's very, very high level.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for beginners, it's very, very good.
Krish NAik: But again, the internal thing. Similarly, like, Keras.
Krish NAik: pretty much functional calls. You really don't understand what happens under the hood.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why, like, once you know the internal things, better stay away from that line channel.
Krish NAik: If you need a very, particular functionality, okay, if you guys can think about any functionality that is only available in Langchain, or only available in Llama Index, then I might think about. But till now, I don't know anything about such functionality.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you know about that, you can tell, okay, Paul, if I need this one, okay? So do the research and tell you later on.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this part I have to…
Krish NAik: Now I will stop sharing. Let's get back to the portal.
Krish NAik: Termint desktop, too.
Krish NAik: Alright, so our entire code is sitting in which folder? The app folder. Everybody? I think everybody knows that.
Krish NAik: Yes, in which folder our entire source code is sitting.
Krish NAik: It's inside the app folder, because whenever you are executing, you're UV gone. The first thing you write, app.
Krish NAik: means the folder. When you come to main. Main stands for the entry point of the application.
Krish NAik: Okay, and inside this main, I'll be having mine.
Krish NAik: Fast API app initialization. So that's why we write app main, okay, and then comes the another app.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, let's start, because I will start our discussion. Okay, before my mean.py, see, config.py, I think everybody is familiar with this file multiple times we have gone through this, yes?
Krish NAik: Yes or no? Guys, please let me know in the chat.
Krish NAik: config file, so many times we have gone through this.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a logging module, because I have implemented a logger. Okay, now this is purely the Python inbuilt logging module that I have added.
Krish NAik: So, I was planning to use Log Guru.
Krish NAik: But I think in later projects, I'll be doing that.
Krish NAik: Because, generally in production, you want structured logs, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Here, you can do it to a certain level, but you don't have a lot of flexibility. So, in a future project, just give me a reminder, like, if I switch back, I will tell you how to work with LogGuru and others.
Krish NAik: Langsmith, no, no, no. Those are different. See, Langsme, perfect, those are observability groups.
Krish NAik: I'm talking from developer perspective, Mutas.
Krish NAik: Every developer will just log in, because we can't write any statement everywhere. Then we won't call a developer, it's pretty much new guy.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, pretty much custom, setup logging. Okay, return type, okay, now checking if running in lambda or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, based on the lambda function name that I'll be getting, okay, logging.me in our rag app that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, now these are… this login… you can actually look into the CloudWatch logs also. So that's why, very specifically, I'm checking that is Lambda available or not, through this particular variable. If Lambda is available, use the stream handler from the logging module, set it to logging.info.
Krish NAik: Don't use debug. I don't prefer in debug you will get much more information. I feel that info is more than enough for now.
Krish NAik: This is the type of formatter. Okay, so date, time, function, label, message that I am passing.
Krish NAik: No, no, this is not a microservice, this is… pure logging implementation, pure Python.
Krish NAik: No microservice.
Krish NAik: Alright, then I will be checking for a log folder, so if you look into my logs…
Krish NAik: Similarly, like, any type of application logs that I'm executing, so you'll be getting all this information. So generally, what happens, we… rather than saving here, what we do, we connect it with a logging service. Any external logging service that you guys have used.
Krish NAik: Let me… There are so many third-party blogging services.
Krish NAik: Datadog, okay? Datadogs, Sentry, okay, they are much more better purpose than toush.
Krish NAik: It's not only for logging, you have to understand. Log stash, yes. I'm looking for such services like AWS, Cloudverse. Again, Prometheus. Purpose of Prometheus is not for logging. I'm telling you only for log. ELK, I don't need that entire stack.
Krish NAik: I need only L from there. Okay, so only logging specific things that I'm asking.
Krish NAik: Greylock, correct. Again, Grafana, not. Grafana, Prometheus, they have a different environment, okay? Log for Python.
Krish NAik: Planck also, I feel that not only… New Relic, see, New Relic, Sentry.
Krish NAik: These are observability tools with much more. So, generally, I call them, like, post-mortem, if you want to do up any application. At every point, if you want to check what is happening, then I prefer working with Sentry, New Relic, or Datadoc.
Krish NAik: No, no, no. Opaque, and these are, like… Mitesh, think about OPC interview.
Krish NAik: certain, facilities, I feel, but again, not such a robust one. Like, New Relic Center, you can't compare them with
Krish NAik: It's a basic level of observability.
Krish NAik: Okay, in production, everybody is using, like, either Datadoc, or New Relic, or Cycling. That has been a standard in the industry, because they charge you. So, for sure, they're…
Krish NAik: level of logs at each function level, at everything that you can debug. So that's pretty much a deep-down post-mortem that we see.
Krish NAik: PiLog4J is, there, it is, PyLog4J is there. Another package anybody has used from Pydentic that they launched, I think Logfire is the name of the package.
Krish NAik: Anybody have used LogFab? Because even I have not used.
Krish NAik: Yes, because in the open source community, I felt that it got a lot of popularity. Logged fans.
Krish NAik: Okay, so any language learning framework for unified view. This comes from the Pyntic community, so… I know it's pretty much open source stuff. Integration can be easy.
Krish NAik: If you want, okay, because as Langsmeeth, we have gone through observability, OPIC this time that we have gone through, I was thinking about integrating log file.
Krish NAik: Probably in some next project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this was him planning, but again, I don't know.
Krish NAik: Not right, actually.
Krish NAik: Just a bit.
Krish NAik: Because in class, showing New Relic and Central Tutor Doc, that is not my preference. I stick to pretty much open source stuff.
Krish NAik: All right, now… In our case, the logging module that I had.
Krish NAik: So, just wait, I think I'm getting on call…
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: So, this was the main logging service that I had.
Krish NAik: So everything, I am saving it within that particular log folder.
Krish NAik: It's an important role for me at length.
Krish NAik: Just guys of weeks.
Krish NAik: The team will be going on vacation. Because of that, you cause…
Krish NAik: Hotel and airlines, I think. Okay, so just wait one minute, then.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so I think we can get back.
Krish NAik: I hope I don't get any more calls.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… Yes.
Krish NAik: So, right now, like, this particular rotation file handler policy that I have taken, really, like.
Krish NAik: This is much more viable when I feel that actually I'm using a persistent logging service, because here, what happens, the multiple times the app starts and restarts. So generally, for development, it's good.
Krish NAik: There again, I got just required to switch off that phone audio capsule.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Sorry for this, guys. Okay. Now, so generally, this is, whenever you are working with rotating, log policies, it's better to have a persistent logging service. Right now, I've just kept it as a dummy implementation, but it's better…
Krish NAik: To have a persistent log in your system.
Krish NAik: So, as you can see, one is the application logs that I have kept, and the other one is the error log. So that's why two log files that I have created here, inside this. So one is responsible for your application, one is for your error.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, when you are doing majorly, when in production, when you look into the logs, how you do it?
Krish NAik: Yes, any rough idea if you guys can tell me?
Krish NAik: If you want to quickly look into some type of error, it comes.
Krish NAik: What is the easiest way?
Krish NAik: That you look into. Crypt and log, okay? Crypt, you can do it.
Krish NAik: a combination of tail, encrypt, those are pretty much like Linux-based commands.
Krish NAik: Okay, start with the key… error keyword.
Krish NAik: Generally, we look into the tail of, like, the last hundred, and on top of that, you can actually look. That's why I've kept a very specific file only to look into the errors. So, if any error comes, it's better directly you can handle it.
Krish NAik: Log analytics, alright, fine, no, third party. Generally direct for developers, like…
Krish NAik: Most of the integrations, if you are working with GitHub, it's much easy. It gives you those alerts if anything that happens. And generally, I have that connected with my Discord and Slack channels, so that every developer gets notified.
Krish NAik: Alright, so… Then, the next step is, okay, for two rotating fine handlers file.
Krish NAik: And here, the limit that I have passed, then comes your formatters.
Krish NAik: Okay. With date and time, that's the thing we are doing. No, Abhishek, everywhere I've kept that formatter, so here you'll be getting the CHC time, so this is the time and format.
Krish NAik: Okay, hmm… No wonder.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Okay, now finally applying the formatters and finally initializing based on that. So, suppress uberly. Now, generally, I am suppressing all these logs, because I know these type of packages can create similarly for line channels and others. You might see a lot of deprecated warning. I am actually suppressing that.
Krish NAik: Yeah, if you want, you can do it. Okay, you can have a list of all the packages where you can do, or on top of your application only, you can set it. I think you can ignore all the warnings.
Krish NAik: So finally, our GitLogger, so this is later on that I'll be calling through. My main logger instance.
Krish NAik: Okay, so a pretty much basic login module. Now I will come into utilities, okay? So, let me go through the utilities once.
Krish NAik: So, these are some util functions. So…
Krish NAik: Validation errors, as you can see, this is a blank implementation. I was planning for some custom validation, but I have not done till…
Krish NAik: Okay, then you have the file validators. Now, file validators, where I'll be using? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: file validators, because here, I'm telling, allow this extension.
Krish NAik: This will be with respect to your upload route. Somewhere, like, if you are uploading anything, in that particular place, I'll be doing. So, the maximum file size, all the settings that I have done, I have kept it separately. During that data ingestion phase, correct?
Krish NAik: Their validate file, okay, if not file or file.fine name, okay, we'll be checking the extension, because of that, a split Python function is there.
Krish NAik: Then, if file extension not in file, validator.allowedExtensions, if you remember, so this is basically the date that I add. If something is not here, then simply we'll say that invalid file type.
Krish NAik: If it has that, we will look into what is the file size, MB, because we have a max MB limit of 50 that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, and then finally.
Krish NAik: your GET file extension calls are there. Then comes your query validator. Now, this is responsible for your RAG response, so here I have kept
Krish NAik: the minimum…
Krish NAik: Question, that means that if any user is passing, keep it 3. But really, I feel that 3 is also less.
Krish NAik: How many of you think that to build a good RAT system, you should have 3 quills?
Krish NAik: Like, 3 characters.
Krish NAik: Because this is a minimum rag portion length.
Krish NAik: So, 3, do you feel that it's correct?
Krish NAik: Because with 3 characters, nothing I can do in the real world. Okay, now we have to think about, okay, with this, I have to do some type of query transformations. Now, just think, in my current document, okay, I ask just attention.
Krish NAik: Okay, so do you really think it will know about English attention word, or attention mechanism, or self-attention, if you're actually…
Krish NAik: So, it's better to clarify. It means that, you can give, multiple suggestions through a…
Krish NAik: Query transformation. Okay, it means that the user will type only attention, and then below, probably a few suggestions that might come up.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is a much better way. Right now, I have taken the Mac
Krish NAik: cushion length, okay? Always remember, when you are sending it to a model, every model has a certain length. For example, with Gemini, you cannot pass it. It means that a very, very big cushion also cannot pass it in one shot.
Krish NAik: So, for example, let me take, Gemini embeddings.
Krish NAik: Germini embeddings.
Krish NAik: this Gemini embeddings, how much it support, let me see.
Krish NAik: Can you see?
Krish NAik: The input token limit.
Krish NAik: 2048. Now, this is a token limit that you have.
Krish NAik: But I feel that 2048 is also huge, but I feel that open source models, like Quinn and others, you can pass more. It is, like, 8K token limits.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always remember that you need to handle that also. So, don't make it very, very big also, that it surpasses the total limit of a certain model.
Krish NAik: Because at the end of the day, we need to make a embedding. It's not an LLM. I hope everybody understands.
Krish NAik: Dive?
Krish NAik: So that's why always remember this limit is there. Every embedding model has a limit, and you can check it from where? Directly look into the MTV leaderboard, okay? And you will see that, Quinn models will have much better and higher values as compared to that.
Krish NAik: That's why, like, Gemini is good, but again, that's where I think… but for more than 99%,
Krish NAik: of you will tell that, yes, that is a pretty much high token limit. Yes, how many of you agree? That 2048 is a very high token limit?
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: You agree, but, really, see.
Krish NAik: Now, when you look into, for example, this is the Gemma version, can you see what is the max tokens? Here you are? 32,000.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 32,000. Really, like, when you try to compare 32,000 with 2,000,
Krish NAik: How many of you agree that there is a huge, huge difference?
Krish NAik: This is only for embedding, yes, Shiva. I'm talking with respect to embedding only, guys. You need to handle these type of things also. So always remember what is the max token limit for your embedding model that you are using.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I have seen people, okay, pasting something big, everything in big.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always remembered that.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Hmm.
Krish NAik: So, here I've taken minimum… the max portion length, I have kept it to 1000 for now.
Krish NAik: Okay, and
Krish NAik: Some… okay, now, the idea is to look for specific SQL patterns, because these are some dangerous patterns. Okay, like drop, okay, then de-truncate. The idea, I've kept it in one place, later on, I'll be using them.
Krish NAik: Then comes validating, the question, for sure we can do it. Okay, hip kosher, or not in quotient.script.
Krish NAik: that I'll be applying a simple Python. You cannot pass anything empty. It means that you have to follow these two rules that I am passing of minimum and max. It cannot be, like, portion cannot be empty. You also know that. Otherwise, how the iterable will work.
Krish NAik: Now, based on that check length, so all those character if and else that I have kept it, minimum and simple if and else logic, and finally the portion will be written.
Krish NAik: Then comes your top K. Now, here, I've not used any default parameter, but you should understand that whenever you are calling your retriever, the top K value, it should be there. Do you think if you pass top k is equal to 0, what will happen?
Krish NAik: Then, top K is equal to 0, so what will happen?
Krish NAik: Nothing will come.
Krish NAik: No, no, see.
Krish NAik: Top K is equal to 0 means a retrie will take place.
Krish NAik: But your top chance, so there, it means that behind the scenes it happens. But actually, for you, the results won't come.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Nothing will be retrieved, don't think in that way. Retriever means retrieval operation that will come, but for you.
Krish NAik: Okay, none of the results will be returned.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for that, another validation that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: So, few simple, simple validations that I have checked. Well, similarly for Dangerous SQL, so the pattern that I've defined about these Dangerous SQL patterns, I have kept it. Now, this can be longer and longer. I'm giving you some intuition. You can keep certain patterns according to your implementations.
Krish NAik: So that… and generally, if you have that approval level, like, yes or no, it's better.
Krish NAik: It's not that for every user, you should keep the access to execute any type of query.
Krish NAik: Alright, then, check dangerous sequels, alright. Then comes sanitize the SQL for display, so,
Krish NAik: Generally, the return type of the LLM, in the result, I only show you the specific SQL string, okay? And I remove other things, because for that, this is a simple cleaning operation or a sanitizing operation on the output of VANA that I have used.
Krish NAik: Then comes your error response. Now, two. One is the error response that I have. Any type of validation errors, in that case, a simple pyrintic implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, if any service is not available, so this I'll be using with respect to my service initialization that I did. When I start my FastApp application, you will see a list of all the service. Okay, so whenever you look into service unavailable, it means that
Krish NAik: some initialization issues, because we have so many services. Okay, it can be with respect to OPIC, it can be with respect to any other service, Pinecone or anything.
Krish NAik: Alright,
Krish NAik: Then comes… okay, internal error responses, I have kept it, but I think in some calls, because this call, I don't think you'll be seeing. Mostly, you'll be looking into the service enablement. Internal errors, because automatically during logging, it will be shown. Then comes your format, file size.
Krish NAik: I think the maximum one that I've given is 50MB limit in my Fast API application. Later on, you can make it much more bigger.
Krish NAik: Then comes truncating text. Okay, in some cases I'll be using, but remember, rarely, like, text truncation that I'll be shown. Can you tell me when I'll be doing it? Truncate text?
Krish NAik: When I don't want to show you all the characters of the response, I just want to show you only few characters. That's why this particular function. This is just a helfer function that I have.
Krish NAik: We'll get 50 error, I think it's not 5.1 error. When you get a particular response at Xpress, I think we'll be getting, for service and approval, 201.
Krish NAik: Samba. Sibar.
Krish NAik: Perfect, right now, no. in Fast API, I've built API, so this is not scary.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is simple. Till now, I've not started my main application only.
Krish NAik: Do you need a break, guys? Let me know. It's 1019.
Krish NAik: Because once I start my main one, it means that a lot of other things will do.
Krish NAik: All right, fine. Let's go ahead for a break. Let's…
Krish NAik: 10, 20, or 10 minutes break.
Krish NAik: Okay, 10.30, we will break the bath.
Krish NAik: So, still now, I've not started the code application, okay? Because every major module is available under this port.
Krish NAik: Perfect. In this, I will stop sharing. Let me start my clock. Everyone, please be back in 10 minutes.
Krish NAik: Actually, only for production it is required, Sankia. Otherwise, not required. Okay, because I told you, if you are using it in production, you can take more than 30-40% of the implementation.
Krish NAik: These are… Very, very common and highly utilized functions at all.
Krish NAik: This is my, I think, 10-minute timer I am switching on. Okay, so guys, I will do my breakfast, and then I'll be back.
Krish NAik: All right. Is there anyone in this batch who has enrolled?
Krish NAik: in UDS 2.0.
Krish NAik: Yes, anyone else here who has enrolled in UDS 2.0?
Krish NAik: That is the Ultimate Data Science Batch. Is there any one?
Krish NAik: No one, no, they're good.
Krish NAik: What is that deliberate? That is the,
Krish NAik: You would use Ultimate Data Science Batch.
Krish NAik: Because if there was anyone, then, like.
Krish NAik: Because I was actually looking into that light class right now.
Krish NAik: That's why. Because there, Mona was teaching, for loop. That's what I thought.
Krish NAik: If somebody's there in this batch, then… Problems, and problems.
Krish NAik: Okay, Mudassar is telling, I think we should decide on the reliability, okay, long-term set of packages. Generally, go for product.
Krish NAik: I feel that, rather than going with land chain, I prefer something product-based packages.
Krish NAik: If somebody is having a product and they are launching their own packages, it's always better to do the integrations in that way.
Krish NAik: Beautiful.
Krish NAik: And generally, if you're applying anything with respect to research, most of the things will be custom implementation. If you get an implementation in a particular package.
Krish NAik: Then you need to look into, because for long-run support for a certain research that you have implemented, in that case, you only need to provide the updates.
Krish NAik: So, in that case, we create our own custom Python package. We keep it as a VIN, so that I can directly download it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, we create wheels, if you know. How many of you have created your own custom packages?
Krish NAik: And deployed it in PWPY.
Krish NAik: Anybody? Done it? Creating own custom packages?
Krish NAik: Okay, because that is where you create the V file for the Python, and then you have to use it.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking, can you share the link of project subscription URLs?
Krish NAik: You can get it from, I think, that one, no?
Krish NAik: Because if you look into LinkedIn, KreshPost, or somewhere, it will be there.
Krish NAik: I don't remember that, but, Krish post in YouTube.
Krish NAik: Because I only do repost of those, okay, I don't post such things.
Krish NAik: But, I feel that, it… Dead…
Krish NAik: The URL is krishnaike.in slash projects or something like that.
Krish NAik: Because I don't remember exactly.
Krish NAik: rishnake.in, go to that website, you will get the list of projects that go in.
Krish NAik: Let me share the URL, I think, yes, they have a, in the URL, krishnak.in slash projects is the URL.
Krish NAik: Okay, yes, I'm a desert.
Krish NAik: Because I knew the URL, but again, like, neither I have opened it, only I have looked into the development phase, okay?
Krish NAik: So, you can look into…
Krish NAik: Some cool projects are up there, generally, for… I feel like, 3 to 4 years of experience, guys, it's…
Krish NAik: You can look into them, but anybody, like, more to 8 to 9 years of experience, few projects might be in your case.
Krish NAik: Good thinking, I know the toughest project That, is taught.
Krish NAik: One is by Sunny, one is by me.
Krish NAik: We try to make things much more complex for everyone.
Krish NAik: Okay, as compared to other minters.
Krish NAik: Atleiba, we'll explore that. When we teach Python, we talk about those type of things.
Krish NAik: If you don't know about that, okay, because here…
Krish NAik: SQL Server, Power BI, when I look into these projects, few things like Notion, React, Planner, Agent, I mean.
Krish NAik: Utility projects, I feel that, yeah, it's good. Smart attendance with superbase.
Krish NAik: Generally for, facial recognition systems I have worked, I prefer working with Kasan and RAW.
Krish NAik: If you have worked with Cassandra or anyone, okay, I prefer that.
Krish NAik: Okay, so really, the number of projects will increase if you look into… because I am the rack guy, I didn't have a lot of time to do any recording.
Krish NAik: Let me see whether any RAG projects are here or not. R, R, R, R, RAG is still…
Krish NAik: Okay, two rack project, what is the talk rack search?
Krish NAik: I think this was discussed in the LLMOps patch. One is AI-powered anime… again, I don't know, really, here, it is internal.
Krish NAik: So, if anybody's interested, you can look into the settings.
Krish NAik: sometimes I put .gitignore file inside that .git node, so that's…
Krish NAik: These are not tough courses, really, like, you have to…
Krish NAik: I think, at least if you try to compare with this project.
Krish NAik: things will be certain easier, but in some cases, you might feel that Azure, Databricks, things that we don't discuss, it might come in. So in those cases, you can very specifically look into that. So, you can look here at advanced, okay? So, in your case, just look into that advanced filter, okay? So I think, is there any filter?
Krish NAik: What that?
Krish NAik: Because, as you can see, this advanced category in the back end, I know there is a filter, but in the front end.
Krish NAik: Okay, no filter, because don't look into beginner. Only look into something intermediate, that I feel, or into…
Krish NAik: the advanced one. In your case, I feel it's much better.
Krish NAik: Holy crap.
Krish NAik: For every…
Krish NAik: project, there is a prerequisite, because, for example, here, so we won't teach you Langrap or Fast API, it's just an implementation that I'll be showing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so every project has its own prerequisites.
Krish NAik: So… Leh.
Krish NAik: Saturday, Sundays, the likelihood drop. B is equal to that you should.
Krish NAik: You have to purchase this bundle, I think. Yes, you have to purchase. Right now, as you can see, it's a separate product that we have kept it. Okay, this is, right now, $9,000. I know that after a few days, it will be $25,000.
Krish NAik: This year, we'll be increasing the price of our courses also.
Krish NAik: Little bit, but not by. At least RAG 2.0, it will be 10K or 12K. And if I include LLMs, it will be a bit higher.
Krish NAik: Alright, yes, everything is pre-recorded, so you can get the access to that.
Krish NAik: By the way, any luck getting Clot's subscription cheaper in case we subscribe as a group? No.
Krish NAik: University has that for private organizations, till now, there is no support. Generally, that's why I told you, get the alternate of Claude. I feel that it's a really good GLM4.7. Even the flash model that they have launched, I think, last week.
Krish NAik: Okay, so people who want cheaper LLMs, one is this option, going with GLM. There's a Chinese
Krish NAik: But, they have a coding plan.
Krish NAik: And, if you want a referral from me, I think you will get some more discount, close to 25. I have purchased… I have this Pro one.
Krish NAik: Okay, and this is 5. So, really, this is good. The other one, or if you want to start monthly, at least do the testing from your end with a 2.7. Okay, I think everyone can spend… if you want to do the testing, if you're actually a developer, it's good.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you want that referral, you can let me know, because this is my personal referral that I'll be sharing with you, and the other one is Minimax.
Krish NAik: Minimax is also good. I've tested both the models. They have a coding plan, but I think, the starter is $10 a year.
Krish NAik: I feel, minimax is much more precise result, lesser research and lesser depth.
Krish NAik: Whereas GLM is better with respect to research. But these models are less intelligent as compared to Sonnet or Opus, or even if you try to compare with GPT.
Krish NAik: And I think I showed you the LLM stats.
Krish NAik: LLM stats… Okay, so the leaderboard…
Krish NAik: Here, if you check, for your own internal use cases, if you are, like, a simple hobby developer, then GLM is really good. Not directly using it in production. So here you can see GLM 4.7 is in fifth place.
Krish NAik: Okay, and minimax M2.0 is in 12 minutes. So, really, like, these are good setup models.
Krish NAik: If you are a purely developer, a coder, then you will be interested. So, I'm using JRM 4.7,
Krish NAik: You can use it with Cloud Code, or with OpenCode, or with Droid. Currently, I've been working with Droid a lot. Droid is also good. Even Goose is there. Goose is also really intelligent.
Krish NAik: Agent ticket.
Krish NAik: So, from here, you can actually check and you can test these things out.
Krish NAik: All right, I think we can get back to our discussion.
Krish NAik: What is dried? Dryed is very similar, so if I show you dried, let me open Christie.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have worked with Cloud Code, then you will understand. So, let me take,
Krish NAik: Okay, now let's what Dwight, I think, to deal with.
Krish NAik: Okay, so you get a very similar interface, and then you can actually do it.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so it's pretty much like lot code, that's why…
Krish NAik: Or, right now in the market, OpenCode is getting a lot of popularity.
Krish NAik: Okay, so for open source developers, they are actually using it. OpenCode is also a really good one, you can test it out. So, this is also a good platform.
Krish NAik: So, in my case, I have integrated my coding plan of GLM everywhere, so I work with open code a lot for the past 2 weeks, I can say.
Krish NAik: Because I got the subscription, but again, I didn't tested it. I tested it after 2 weeks or 3 weeks.
Krish NAik: These are some really cool ones.
Krish NAik: But purely developer-centered. If you are a developer, it's good.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me just switch back, yes.
Krish NAik: Rob is also what he is, like, actually, like,
Krish NAik: In the wrap, opening a separate window becomes a problem. That's why I use that ghosty terminal.
Krish NAik: Okay, that was the main purpose, because in my screen, like, 4 monitors and 4 multiple terminal loopers. But in RAP, that particular feature of just keeping it in a separate window, that becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys, so let's start our discussion.
Krish NAik: T3 chat, I'm not excluded.
Krish NAik: B.
Krish NAik: Another one is gustel now, like, I've not installed it, I was actually explored this one. Okay, this is also…
Krish NAik: very famous, like, I feel that a lot of developers are switching. In the Reddit community, you can see the number of stars for this project is 48, okay? And really, people have been switching to Goose.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the other project I was tracking. Later on, I will do the testing, and I will let you know exactly, like, whether it's good or not.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's start our code discussion.
Krish NAik: So, config, login config utilals I've gone through, now I will start with a main.py implementation. Okay? So, through main.py, all my major calls that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now this is my main.py as your entry point of our application. Okay, or basically the fast KPI implementations will be available here.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so first of all, a few common, like, from typing import, optional, then some fast API-related things that I have, then I think, Fast API responses, date and time, path lips says, shuttles, okay, so a few common boilerplates.
Krish NAik: Now, from config, I'm importing the settings, if you remember. Okay, so this is my core settings initialization from my config.py.
Krish NAik: Then I'm setting up my logger service. Okay, so here's, right now, majorly, I've used in this script, setup underscore logging. I've not used gait underscore logger.
Krish NAik: Then comes my document service. Okay, now, because in the import only, I'll be going to the main, one.
Krish NAik: Now, with respect to the document service that I have, okay, so this is my main document service.py.
Krish NAik: Now, what are the libraries that I have used here?
Krish NAik: In this one, because I started with unstructured. If you remember, like, last week.
Krish NAik: I actually… this was my main document service, and later on, I added a hybrid chunker from Docklink, so that implementation is, you know, separate. So, I can switch from Docklink to unstructured at any point of time in the code, so that particular support that I have.
Krish NAik: So, initially, tick token. What is the purpose of tick token?
Krish NAik: I think everybody should know.
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me. Take token.
Krish NAik: shunking correct, cost calculation, because you can actually use tokenization correct, token counting correct. Okay.
Krish NAik: For all that. Everyone is familiar, it's good to do any calculation, correct?
Krish NAik: Okay, now, I'm initializing a login instance for…
Krish NAik: our, ragav.document service, so this is the initialization that I'll be using for my RAG service.
Krish NAik: And in this instance, one is parse document, okay? So, these are all certain conditions, let's…
Krish NAik: focus on the core logic that I have.
Krish NAik: So, file name, with the extensions, traffic.uwarf, file name in TXT, markdown, CSV, log, JSON, okay, that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Using fast text read, as you know, in unstructured, you can do multiple, so through this, I am actually checking the extensions. I think that .log, this support is directly not enabled, because
Krish NAik: This implementation, actually, I'm not using it. Okay, so this is a dummy implementation of unstructured. If you remember, in my lambda.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, there is a true and false condition. I always test it, like, useDoclink is equal to true or false. It means that in the environment, if PyTorch is getting called, then I will switch to unstructured.
Krish NAik: Okay, so because of that ERM64, I was actually doing this switch from unstructured to Doppling, or from Doppling to unstructured. But as my current deployment architecture has been moved to x86, so I know the type of issues with respect to Dopplink. So my core service will be based on Dopplink.
Krish NAik: Alright, and my chunking strategy is the hybrid chunker from Dockley, in the last class adaptation.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is my, core logic. Now, a few Unicode errors, this also operation. So, if you remove logging… the number of logging lines, automatically the code will become much more smaller, okay? So, logit.info using structured library for the file extension that I have.
Krish NAik: Then, inside this, I have… so this is the first time with respect to parsing the document.
Krish NAik: And can you see here? This is the actual function through which you do.
Krish NAik: In notebooks, you guys have worked with this one.
Krish NAik: the actual core function. The rest, everything is Python value, but this is the actual function, partition.
Krish NAik: How many of you remember in unstructured, you guys have used partition?
Krish NAik: Yes.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, see, everything, always try to look into the core functionality.
Krish NAik: Right now I have disabled the OCR, because for unstructured, only I was working with ERM. Okay, so that's why. Like, I have a separate image for OCR support, where Tesseract comes pre-installed.
Krish NAik: Then the other one is there without the OCR, so…
Krish NAik: And as you know, that even in docklink or in unstructured, like, multiple type of OCR backends that can be used.
Krish NAik: Simple example, easy OCR, rapid OCR, okay, in the class we have discussed. But for now, I'm using the strategy Fast Moon. It means that no OCR. It works without the Tesseract.
Krish NAik: So, only one line. If you really think about remove everything, try block, okay, this is the actual thing that I'm doing.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in notebook, I will remove everything, so only this particular line is important to me.
Krish NAik: Then comes the chunking. So, the parsing is done, after parsing comes your chunking. So, for chunking, like, tick token directly that I have applied.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the GPT-4 encoding strategy that I have used here.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much, you can see, directly I'm using tokens. Here, I have not used any third-party library implementation. Okay, so I was planning to use everything based on some poor packages only, rather than taking support from Langchen or any others.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this function is responsible to do your chunking. Can you use chunky here? Yes, it can get chunk.
Krish NAik: There is no issue in that.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can use strong key, or you can use, like,
Krish NAik: text splitters module from LanChain, okay, those things, you can do it. Chunk is also good, it's a separate package by field address.
Krish NAik: Alright, so the final, chunking function that I have. So here, the core package is tick token.
Krish NAik: through TikTok, when you can do everything.
Krish NAik: Public.
Krish NAik: Now,
Krish NAik: if you remember, in my config file, I have my settings. So, what was my chunking settings? The chunk size and the chunk overlap?
Krish NAik: Anybody remembers?
Krish NAik: It was 512.50 that I have used. Please have a check in the config.py.
Krish NAik: Right now, when I'm creating the chunk, or sample metadata also, that I have created. Now, guys, this implementation results actually don't be reflected in AI, because I am actually using talk links. Okay, later on, I'll be telling that. But through TikToking, you can do that.
Krish NAik: Now, chunk test semantic. Now, what is this? This is a simple split test with semantic chunks with the same chunk library. Okay, let me show you the same chunk.
Krish NAik: Now, if you don't… if you want to do chunk DY API,
Krish NAik: This is a pure, lighter version and a lighter implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: As you can see.
Krish NAik: Can you see it has a built-in support for tokenizers, OpenAI, tick token, and Having further. So, this is a very, very simple implementation. It means that you don't need any third-party libraries directly if you have this.
Krish NAik: then you can create semantic, chunk, and you respect the boundaries also. This is a really good one, a very lightweight package. If you want to work with semantic chunking, okay, you can use this.
Krish NAik: So, I have just used this one. Now, this is a developer library. If you look into the updates of this package.
Krish NAik: Semantic chunk, you can use it. It's, like, context-aware chunking also you can do, or semantic chunk. Generally, I don't prefer always working with semantic chunks, I prefer much more context of it.
Krish NAik: If you look into the release history, the last update was October 2825.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the main problem. It means that ESG is semantic chunking will happen, but this package will never get updated. But I note the core functionality is there, so probably later on I might need to update this.
Krish NAik: Because the support is with transformers, if something that changes in the Transformers library, again, this library will be dedicated. Okay? So I was looking for something lightweight. Okay, so that's why I have used this particular implementation with unstructured. Because in our docklink, it's a total different implementation.
Krish NAik: How to check which live data package is good?
Krish NAik: Generally, like, it's…
Krish NAik: Okay, if you go into here… okay, so because I saw that close to 542, I know not a lot of people, because only one functionality is there in this package. So, if anybody is looking for only this functionality of semantic chunking, then it's really good.
Krish NAik: And you can see, it's very close to semantic text filter that is implemented.
Krish NAik: So, that's why I've taken this, but again, guys, for you, you can decide, you can pick anything. Chunky, okay, or Langchain, Llama Index, or Docklink that I have picked.
Krish NAik: Wonder.
Krish NAik: Okay, so here, my main tick token encoding one I have done, then from same chunk, import chunk clarify through this, that, the implementation that we need to do. Now, the chunk size definition, we have already passed it on our config. From there, it will be picked up.
Krish NAik: Using same chunks on top of our main text, we'll be applying the chunk card. And finally, all the information. So right now, this is a blank list. Later on, on top of which, I'll be performing an append operation. You can see chunks.append.
Krish NAik: with certain level of metadata. Okay, so this is actually chunk metadata that I have kept it, which I can append it to our main Pinecode index.
Krish NAik: Generally, in Saravedra, the question that you are asking, in terms of performance, you have to… you can do an initial testing. I don't think you can get direct scripts, but, you can do the testing by yourself.
Krish NAik: By taking 3 initial… initialization instances of those libraries that you plan on top of the same data, and try to check that, and you can compare the results by looking into that, because that testing needs to be done from your side.
Krish NAik: San is telling in this main method, two methods of chunk implementation has done. Okay, my, see, one is the, chunk without semantic, one is the normal chunk, and one is the semantic one. San Kumar.
Krish NAik: The previous one, it is pure, like, directly, if you try to apply, based on the logic.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that is just the natural junky, but I have kept one implementation of semantic chunky. As you guys have worked with advanced chunkers, that's why I've kept this semantic implementation also.
Krish NAik: Because when I start building a project, it's not my priority to use any chunkle. Later on, I can switch to any chunky. I always look into the main pipeline, the input and output that I'm getting. In between those things, it can always update.
Krish NAik: Perfect. Now… This is my chunk metadata that I can store it in Pinecone indexes.
Krish NAik: Alright, so once the chunking is done, okay, so…
Krish NAik: Later on, like, heading, page numbers now, really, this needs to be thrown by your parser, then it becomes much easier for your chunking to keep these type of informations.
Krish NAik: Vipin is asking what is the difference between
Krish NAik: A normal chunking and semantic chunking. Bephin, please go through the lectures.
Krish NAik: Really, I have taken chunking classes separately.
Krish NAik: If you have not really gone through that.
Krish NAik: Okay, all right now.
Krish NAik: Then I have a function to get our document stats. Simple statistics about your document.
Krish NAik: Here, the main parse document, if you remember this parse document function that I have defined in the first step that I am calling.
Krish NAik: Because really, the scrolling with respect to the boot is pretty high.
Krish NAik: Okay, so devget, okay, the stats, okay, now this will return few file type metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this metadata also you can paint with every chunk, but you have to pick, like, which is much more relevant.
Krish NAik: Okay, because file-related metadata is also good, then you can actually, relate that to this. This chunk is related to this file.
Krish NAik: Because I told you, till now, I have not shown you any good example of metadata. In Project 3, I'll be showing you, and even the research paper that we have metadata generated from IBM. Okay, so there, the main implementation is, based on metadata generation.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is only the file stat information that you can append it to your metadata.
Krish NAik: And finally comes parse and chunk with context. Now, this is where I'll be calling my main. If you really look into parse document chunk. So, it means that the functions that I've defined above, I'm just calling them here.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whenever you look into, these are all my custom functions that I am calling.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, I am initializing them. Okay, so that's why text is equal to parse document, chunks is equal to chunk text, text semantic, and, my original text that I am getting from the file that I am passing, with the chunk size definition that I have done.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Abhijit is telling this version is not yet published in the report. I think this is published, guys, please let me know.
Krish NAik: Please let me know, because I think this should be available in your port.
Krish NAik: Shiva confirmed it said, okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, as I was doing the deployment with, ERL64 and X86 and 64 architectures, in that case, now, this is a condition.
Krish NAik: Now, here you can see one directly I can use this implementation. The core is this one.
Krish NAik: If not, settings.useDoclink. Okay, now this is a Boolean value that I told, even in lambda, useDoclink is equal to true and false, based on that condition. Otherwise, directly, the dockling implementation that I can take. So, from dockling, I have used the hybrid chunker. Hybrid chunker and docklink does a context of our chunking.
Krish NAik: Okay, it's not semantic chunking. The type of chunking is different. You can look into the implementation of that. Doc link.
Krish NAik: I think hybrid… Jungle.
Krish NAik: This is the implementation. It actually respects the boundaries, so I prefer this much more to better, but here you have to maintain the minimum number of characters within the chunk.
Krish NAik: So I feel that, that thing you need to really work on. So this is a simple implementation. So I have actually used this one. So this is pretty much a context of our chunking implementation.
Krish NAik: Arum, the repo has been changed in the last class. Please go through that.
Krish NAik: I think in my motion, just with somebody is saying, I don't have the access to Rippo, but
Krish NAik: I think in, there I have added it.
Krish NAik: I'll delete that.
Krish NAik: You can see here, please check, in the last class I have done it, people who are telling you.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, San is asking why I'm using Unstructured and docklink.
Krish NAik: Because I thought about to include… because, see, when I look into my results, I feel that semantic chunking was not giving me very good results. So, I switched to context-averse chunking. But again, the problem was, during my deployment, I was facing the issue with the PyTorch backend. If you are working with Dockling, Dockling uses PyTorch. It means that without PyTorch, you cannot use Dockling.
Krish NAik: So I was planning that without a PyTorch backend, can I do the deployment or not? Because of that, certain try and exception blocks are there, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, first of all, so right now, the core logic that comes, here you can see one is a docklink service, can you see here?
Krish NAik: this docklink. So, right now, this is my document service. It's based on my unstructured, but my docklink service, there is another service that I have. So, that service, I was actually testing it. Okay, so which one works? So, I switched…
Krish NAik: too unstructured, just because of ERM64 support, which was not available for top 3. Okay, so that's why. It means that… that's why I've taken both the libraries here. If this doesn't work in my deployment, I will switch to this.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, then finally comes your docklink service from EC, as you have this parse and jump document.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, parsing and chunking can be done in one shot through Dockly. Okay, so that's why this particular implementation, if you look into… Okay, so first of all, this convert document into a labeled awareness. This is the first step. Okay, and then I'm applying the hybrid chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, so pretty much a simple implementation. This is the actual thing, only two lines that you need to do the implementation. Rest of the code are, again, boilerplate with try, accept, and logging data.
Krish NAik: Because I have shown you the implementation, how many lines of code that you actually need to do. It's very, very less.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once you have done the parsing of the document directly, so this is your main document converter. After the document converter, you can apply. So, only two lines of code that is required from it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let me get back to our main, document service. So, that's why I've taken that, okay. If that fails, then switch. So, this is a simple try block that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Use Docklink for context-averse chunking, then I'm directly calling my parse and chunk document. Okay, and finally, I will return the chunks. So once the chunks are written, then I know that the next step is… what is the next step? Embedding. That will come into the picture.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, the means, purpose of this document service is what? It will read the document once the document is, it will convert it into chunks.
Krish NAik: Now, how you are converting into chunks, it's totally up to you. I have kept the support for unstructured as well as dockly, both. Now, based on my deployment problem that I had.
Krish NAik: Okay, son, really, like, you can use anything, it's not like you have to use only one thing.
Krish NAik: Josephine and Dumas, can you please share the notion link? Just join the batch.
Krish NAik: Alright, I will be sharing it.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is a core document service that I have, so a very similar implementation in Docklin that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, so if you look into… so, first of all, the document converter core implementation. Okay, so here, so this is the actual code, which is related to Dockley. How many of you remember?
Krish NAik: I will be focusing on the core C, if for everything, if not part, I think everybody understand that. These are simple conditions. If this is not available, okay, then automatically this error, import error will come, that docklink is not installed. If dockling is installed.
Krish NAik: Then one error will come that, okay, I am, the PyTorch backend is not available, as I showed in the last class, the error that I was getting. So your core implementation is this one.
Krish NAik: With respect to…
Krish NAik: So when I'm doing this, what is the meaning of this converter? I'm doing a parsing operation, yes or no?
Krish NAik: Yes or no. This is the core parsing operation.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, even with unstructured, also, I faced that ERM issue.
Krish NAik: I thought I will switch, because, in my deployment mode, as I was only testing unstructured with that PDF. Only all docs I have removed, I only kept that unstructured PDF package, but there also, it was free.
Krish NAik: Then, finally, I moved to… from ARM64 to that architecture, x86.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Then comes your hybrid chunker implementation, because the parsing is done. If the parsing is done, what is the next step?
Krish NAik: your chunking, that's why your hybrid, chunker that you have. Okay. Now, if you really look into, this is the main line of code.
Krish NAik: That you can work. Now here, I'm using the…
Krish NAik: token type with respect to tick token plus, because at every point of time, if you're working with tick token, it gives you, functionalities that I can use. I can count all those tokens, so for that case, I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Because, in the response type, you will see that, the total number of chunks, and even I think I am sending the total number of tokens inside a chunk.
Krish NAik: Because I was planning to send that information. Then it becomes much more clearer that when I'm sending that context, actually, that, what is that, chance?
Krish NAik: Alright, so,
Krish NAik: Now, generally, it's better if you're working with OpenAI, tick token is the most recommended package that you should always work with, because Tick Token comes with GPT-4 encodings.
Krish NAik: Well, right now, this is our main chunker implementation that I have. Okay, and then again, finally, once I have my, the chunking implementation will be done, because this is the initialization. Later on, I'll be calling this particular function.
Krish NAik: That I have defined it here. Chunk with hybrid. Similarly, this parsing. So, for everything, there is a function. Later on, I'll be calling those functions one by.
Krish NAik: Mithesh is asking, can we change OpenAI to GPT-5 Nano?
Krish NAik: Yes, you can use, because I think I am using a GPT-40, you can switch to GPT-5 Nano, that is much more cheaper. 4.0 is really a costly model, or you can use GPT-4O Mini, I prefer that. So, 5 nano is also fine, there won't be any issues.
Krish NAik: Because,
Krish NAik: Whenever you are working with TikToken, it's recommended always that, yes, the encoding time, the encoding type is by default supported with GPT, so any type of GPT model that can be used.
Krish NAik: So, anything from the OpenAI family.
Krish NAik: But, generally for… if I'm working with Quinn, then I won't be working with tick token. Like, I won't be using the encoding of tick token, you have to understand. I can use tick token to count the total number of tokens and those things I can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, but the actual encoding type, it's not preferred. If you are working with Quinn-based models.
Krish NAik: You can test it, because really, I have not done any testing with 5 nano.
Krish NAik: I don't feel the model is really good or up to mark, for rank-based solutions, Matesh.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is my convertDocument first function, then I have my chunk with hybrid. Now, this is the core initialization part. So, first of all, with respect to tick-token embeddings that I have taken, and this initializer, I will be calling it later on.
Krish NAik: Now, the question comes, once the chunks are available to me, it means that the return type… so, if you look into this chunker, now, where I'm calling this chunker.
Krish NAik: So, this will actually generate your main, chunking operation call that I have taken into account.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, you will be having your raw chunks, then comes your post-processing of the chunks. So, finally, the result that I'll be getting, the merge chunks. Okay, how many of you know? Because if you remember our dev format function that we do, we're used to concatenate all those chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that operation, sometimes it's helpful, but again, not in every case. I have taken a simple implementation of this.
Krish NAik: Currently, merge difficult to none. Okay, later on, you can update this variable.
Krish NAik: So, if current merge is equal to none, so current merged is equal to chunk, it means that the original chunk information
Krish NAik: Sometimes it's a good practice that if you feel that if you have a single paragraph, and if you feel that the chunk is broken, you can actually combine those chunks and keep a new chunk.
Krish NAik: So, this is possible using the hybrid chakra.
Krish NAik: Okay, so merge pierce is equal to true.
Krish NAik: Okay, if you have the same heading. So, there's a little bit unique shankar you can explore. Previously, I've not taught direct on Dockling-based chunkers, but yes, this feature is available. So, I feel that this is a good and a powerful feature.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Then comes merging if the current chunk is undersized. See, sometimes with hybrid chunking, the problem is
Krish NAik: the amount of chunk, or basically the number of tokens in a chunk, you might feel that only one line is here, or two lines. So it's a good thing that you should maintain a minimum token size.
Krish NAik: So that's why here, in this particular, you can see, max token is 512.
Krish NAik: Now, this is a custom implementation on top of the hybrid chunker that I have done, because when I directly, blindly applied the hybrid chunker, I got close to 290 charts.
Krish NAik: Okay, then I feel that, really, the number of chunks are high. It means that I need a solution.
Krish NAik: Okay, then what I did, I changed, so I added the condition where I kept at, okay, I will be taking at least the minimum, tokens, it means that you need minimum 256.
Krish NAik: So that's why this is a custom logic on top of the hybrid chunk.
Krish NAik: Because the result of the hybrid chunker, I failed at.
Krish NAik: More than, like, 290 chunks were written.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I added this implementation on top of that.
Krish NAik: How many of you got it?
Krish NAik: Because when you do the testing on top of a raw implementation, when you look into the result, you have to look. Because just think about, for a single PDF, 290 chunks, it means that at every point of time.
Krish NAik: like, to generate… to… it means that if you want your LLM to generate something good, it means that you need to pass the context, and just think about your passing, even top 5 chunks. One option was me, okay, my top K chunks, I can include more. That was one option.
Krish NAik: But I feel that even if I use 25, Then also, somewhere.
Krish NAik: Really, like, whether everything will be related or not.
Krish NAik: That can be one problem. So it's better to keep, conditional logic that at least, okay, that minimum time. You can reduce this number, but at least have
Krish NAik: 150 tokens.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that you should have anything more than 100 at least. Because if the return type in your chunk is only 10 tokens, do you feel that
Krish NAik: if that context is selected during your retrieval. Do the LLM… will the LLM will generate good results? Yes or no telling me?
Krish NAik: So sometimes, just use your mind based on the results, because I know you know the logic, so you can take that decision.
Krish NAik: So, always do the testing, because I always do a core testing. If it fails, I apply my own logic on top of that.
Krish NAik: So, always remember that. So, in your chunks, apply your logic rate, minimum token should be there.
Krish NAik: But in some cases, it can be a problem also. Can anybody tell me when it can be a problem?
Krish NAik: Because every implementation comes with pros and cons.
Krish NAik: Yes, can anybody tell me when it can be a problem?
Krish NAik: In coding it will be a problem.
Krish NAik: Yes, encoding type of task, where the minimum number of tokens, we take bigger numbers.
Krish NAik: Even with respect to markdown documents, if you think, if you simply have an heading.
Krish NAik: Okay, and in that heading, if you have just one link.
Krish NAik: Then also it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, that's why in some cases I feel that it's a problem, but again, you have to actually analyze your main chunks.
Krish NAik: But it should not be like that, you are generating a lot of chums. Because I felt that for that climate, document I uploaded, it generated, I think, 290 chums.
Krish NAik: I felt that the… it's not good, so I kept it. So, you can play with this, because, see, simply this number that I'm sharing with you, you also know that this needs to be decided by you. It's really a hyperparameter.
Krish NAik: So, use anything above 120, because to generate good context. Just think.
Krish NAik: If you are working with top K, okay, in every K, the minimum number of token is 120. So, 120 into 5, when you do, you are getting 600 tokens. So, always thinking that what is the total number of tokens that are at least getting for your context generation.
Krish NAik: It is important. If you have lesser number of tokens, it doesn't matter if you are getting very high. So, the total number of tokens plays a crucial role.
Krish NAik: There's this part here, what I'm trying to explain to everyone.
Krish NAik: Because these are, like, when you do it in real time, you will get these problems.
Krish NAik: Rabin value of the minimum token, any chunk less than 250 will be ignored.
Krish NAik: It won't be ignored. It will be kept as a separate chunk.
Krish NAik: We will try to, first of all, take that condition.
Krish NAik: Okay, minimum 256, but think about the final condition that kept where only the last content was there. Then we will try to look for a chunk, and we can try to do the merging. So, that's why you have to think about, in real world, the scenario is different. And really, we don't do. So, like, here also, I can keep
Krish NAik: another custom logic inside that, that, okay, in some cases, if you have only, like, 100 tokens to present.
Krish NAik: in those conditions that, okay, I can be out of this logic.
Krish NAik: And the result of the hybrid chunker, I can apply it to a second level of chunking, only for those chunks where I have
Krish NAik: So, that is another level of implementation, but you can handle in multiple ways, if the core condition fails. Right now, I have taken, so I'm telling… so, this implementation has a con, because here, minimum 256, I have taken, but you can actually reduce it if you want.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, here, check we should merge with the current chunk or not, because this merging strategy I've applied, because to maintain this minimum number of chunk.
Krish NAik: Because in my case, I was getting the chunks, majorly in mine, chunk results, I felt. There are around 30-40 tokens, not more than that. So I performed this operation.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes merge if the current chunk size is underside, and combined won't exceed. So, this is a simple condition.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, again, pretty much, when you will be working, you will be implementing custom conditions. Everyone in RAG does it.
Krish NAik: Now, then come the chunk metadata. Okay, now the metadata that we can extract it.
Krish NAik: through Docklinks, because Docklink can extract certain level of metadata, but again, not a very detailed metadata.
Krish NAik: Because most of the time, you have to create your own custom functions to do that. Finally, I'm keeping all this information, because later on, with every chunk, I have to append the information of every metadata.
Krish NAik: How many of you remember, like, for every chunk, The metadata was there.
Krish NAik: Yes? How many of you remember that?
Krish NAik: Because this is file-level metadata, metadata.json, so don't be confused. This is file-level metadata, okay? And then when you have your chance level, so this particular information.
Krish NAik: Chunk, index, token count, this information, you can actually keep it.
Krish NAik: If you… even you can look this information in Pinecone. In Pinecone also, this will be available.
Krish NAik: Okay, how many of you looked into Pinecone? In Pinecone, also, the same implementation will be available.
Krish NAik: Yeah, so chunk-level metadata. And later on, your final metadata can be a combination of both the metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay? It means that your file-level metadata, then you can actually relate, okay, from this file, actually, I've taken. Right now, in this metadata, if you look.
Krish NAik: Can you really see that this chunk is of which file? If I directly show you this chunk.
Krish NAik: Can you tell me from which file that I have taken?
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: When you look into only this file, just check.
Krish NAik: Tokens, Saurabh is telling, just reconfirming, the tokens are part of Chunk, exactly. Tokens has to be part of chunk.
Krish NAik: never seen it in Pinecone weapon, please log in into your, Pinecone index, the same information that you'll be getting, so…
Krish NAik: I don't remember exactly in which one, okay, PineChoon account.
Krish NAik: Because again, I updated so many Pinecone accounts.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, show to me. Can you see this is the actual text that got chunked?
Krish NAik: So here, I'm not…
Krish NAik: Okay, later on, I think I have taken it from the metadata, but here can you see the core file?
Krish NAik: You should always know that it's very good, because metadata filtering actually helps you to do much more optimized results, if you feel.
Krish NAik: Beautiful.
Krish NAik: Alright. Rahul, everything is false, something is wrong? Okay.
Krish NAik: If it doesn't work later on, I will… Hold it.
Krish NAik: This is a Junk and metall.
Krish NAik: Okay…
Krish NAik: Where is poor, there is no…
Krish NAik: I don't think there shares any score here.
Krish NAik: I don't have a score, I think.
Krish NAik: Which one here? This one, so…
Krish NAik: Okay, this represents, basically, the quality of the chunks. It's an internal thing that they have in Bangkok. It's not in everywhere this is available. So right now, you have to think about the result that you are doing. So, this is a search operation.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the search ID is just fine. So, based on that, this is the score that is being written. Okay, so don't think if you remove this particular implementation, because I think it will be there, but it's based on, like, update via metadata list, so for that, so we have that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now let's get back.
Krish NAik: Okay, so where was my app on top link?
Krish NAik: Survivable.
Krish NAik: Alright, my poor Docklin service, so this is the main one.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the metadata marching, okay?
Krish NAik: Now, merge page numbers. Okay, now, this is also one implementation if you want to keep it, because right now, it's much more about the chunk metadata.
Krish NAik: Because I feel that page numbers, if you want to save it, it's good for your own references. Later on, you can actually look into that. So that's why I'm trying to extract that through metadata.origin. Like, I'm trying to extract it through headings. Now, these functionalities are directly available through docklinks that I am accessing.
Krish NAik: So, I'm just checking that, first of all, if the page numbers are available or not, because you have to look into the results of Dockling, and then only you can extract the information. If it is not available, nothing you can.
Krish NAik: So it's a good practice to keep all the information there.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then finally, all the merged chunks, so I think I'll be apparenting it in my main current one.
Krish NAik: Okay, so merge chunks, which is a blank list.
Krish NAik: Now, convert to format compatible with existing cache or vector storage. For vector storage, I have this embedding service. It means that the return type of this docklink service or the document service will directly be called in embedding.
Krish NAik: Now, in which format if you want, because the chunk that you are doing, okay, how you want to maintain all the chunk information? So, first of all, if you want a hierarchy-level implementation, like headings.
Krish NAik: Page numbers, captions, now, these are all the written type of docklink. It might not be available in my case. You have to understand, if your document doesn't have these type of metadata information.
Krish NAik: Okay, then nothing that can be done. So a simple logic everywhere, if, if, if that I have.
Krish NAik: If it is not available, simply it will skip, but I am trying to maintain that to
Krish NAik: Right, to keep these operations.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: And finally, the chunk data will be looking something like this, okay? Now, somewhere better, I can say.
Krish NAik: for every chunk text, the chunk index, headings, speech number, talk items, okay, and finally, I am appending all this result.
Krish NAik: For every chunk that I'm, in the result. So, which is a blank list. So, within this particular list, all of your chunks will be available.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: So the metadata part is done.
Krish NAik: Now, okay, now this is a function that I was only checking that whether Docklink is available in our runtime environment. So, by applying this function in my core service, or document service, I was having a chat whether Docklink is installed or not.
Krish NAik: Holy cow.
Krish NAik: Can you see here, if this condition gets getDoclink status, if this particular function returns false? So, for that, I have this fallback condition also.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this fallback condition is the unstructured condition.
Krish NAik: So, in the same script, I have kept it. Like, in Docklink, in the unstructured script, I have kept the fallback condition to docklink. Similarly, in the docklink script, I have kept the fallback condition to unstructured.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, you can create a much more single optimized file, but, always remember, because I have not done the optimization for this file, but actually, docklink underscore service and document. I can remove both of this file, and I can use only one, which is the docklink service.
Krish NAik: Okay, so just remember that, because this only for deployment purpose I have created, Otherwise, there was no need.
Krish NAik: So, docklings, so always, select out of one whether to go for unstructured, whether to go for docklink.
Krish NAik: I will prefer Docklink much more, because my chunking is directly on top of Docklink. That's why I know Docklink can do the parsing, as well as it can do the chunking. My preference will be for Docklink, as compared to all-stock chunk.
Krish NAik: So this is the first level, then in the next thing, once the document is ready, then comes your embedding service.
Krish NAik: So, for embedding, what is the service that I am using, guys? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: for embedding.
Krish NAik: two services are there. One is the fine phone, where I'll be saving the embeddings, the other one is the OpenAI.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… First of all, async OpenAI, package that I have kept.
Krish NAik: Okay, and a few other conditions while I'm loading up my settings. From here, I'll be getting what type of embedding model that I want to use.
Krish NAik: So, this is the embedding service. First of all, I'm just checking whether the API key is available. Okay, then the client initialization. Can you see here? Async OpenAI, and here I am passing the OpenAI API key that I have initialized. Then, self.model, text embedding 3, small, then you have your dimensions.
Krish NAik: Okay, then comes your self.queryCatcher now, you have to remember.
Krish NAik: Are we doing the catching of the embeddings? Yes or no?
Krish NAik: Y espano.
Krish NAik: Are we doing the catching of our embedding? So, we are doing… so that's why this service. So, I implemented Redis later on, so just for Redis, you need it. If you're not working with Redis, remove this link.
Krish NAik: Okay, because this is an optional catching service, as you know, it's not necessary that you have to implement with catching.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, generate embeddings. So, for generate embeddings, which package are you using? The OpenAI package as simple as that.
Krish NAik: So, now, everywhere I will be… so, from here, you have to understand, my catching service will come. It means that, first, I will look into the catch.
Krish NAik: If it is available, it'll catch it.
Krish NAik: Then, pick from the catcher. If it's not available in the catcher, it means that you have to generate the embedding. Okay, so that's why that if catcher is available, so check that, the availability is there or not. So that's why everywhere, you will see that a lot of if conditions.
Krish NAik: anywhere I'm doing it, whether for embedding, whether for the RAG response, whether for the RAG query everywhere, this AFib condition will come, just for the catch-up.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Oh.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, like, this is the main if condition that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, if the condition fails in simple terms. Okay, now these are a few flat variables that I'll be showing you, because the catch a hit condition, right, initially, I know that it will be 0. Later on, you can update it if the catch a miss condition comes. So, later on, zero, I will be
Krish NAik: Change in various variables, so pretty much flat variables, I can say.
Krish NAik: If I text in numerates, so directly I'll be getting this self-query. So this is directly from query, from Redis, I can fetch the service, like the catch-it key and the catch-it value through this. And the catcher type, the key, if you remember, we had four types of keys. The embedding key.
Krish NAik: the RAG key, okay, so based on these keys, so this is a catcher type for embedding that I'll be using.
Krish NAik: If captured and embedding in captured, so embedding is what happened.
Krish NAik: Okay, if it is not available else, embedding.append is equal to none, so pretty much a blank condition.com.
Krish NAik: Now, just to handle so much of Cache, a lot of code has been applied, but actually, this is the piece of code.
Krish NAik: For your embedding, guys. Can you see here? A bit self.client embeddings?
Krish NAik: Can you see our async embeddings implementation from OpenAI?
Krish NAik: generate embeddings for Uncatched. So this is actually, if you're not working with Redis, this piece of line of code that you require.
Krish NAik: To do your direct implementation of embedding.
Krish NAik: You don't need any… Yeah, other… Like, packages.
Krish NAik: So, directly, it can be done.
Krish NAik: How many of you get this? So, first of all, I'm checking the catching. If it… if we don't have it in the catch-it, we will generate it through the OpenAI package. The implementation is based on async call, so an asynchronous call that will be made for your embedding generation.
Krish NAik: So this is much better implementation, the embedding processing is much faster.
Krish NAik: Now, once you have this, so we will… now, if the new embeddings are generated, what we will do in the next one?
Krish NAik: You have to capture the embedding CS or no?
Krish NAik: Most of the lines of code you will see just because of catching.
Krish NAik: Because actually, if there was no catcher, the number of lines of code will be much easier, you have to understand that.
Krish NAik: Right now, I'm not specified in batches. It's pretty much ASIC. It means, like, parallel execution of multiple, chunks. For that, you can do it on Zoom.
Krish NAik: I have not set any badge right now.
Krish NAik: Batch operations will come during uploads.
Krish NAik: So whenever you are working with a batch, you have to understand that operation will be coming from… even OpenAI has a limit. It means that if you start hitting the OpenAI API continuously for 10,000 chunks, okay, you will get an error. You have to use some type of time.slip, at least for 1 second or two seconds.
Krish NAik: The limit is it.
Krish NAik: So that limit you have to respect, and based on that in your API, you have to switch to time.sleep for at least 1 second or 2 seconds, that I feel.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once my new embeddings are generated, I have to put them into the catches, so here is…
Krish NAik: to put them into the catcher based on my main key query value, so this is the main catcher value, the structure that I have. The total text length, the main opening embedding model, and the actual key.
Krish NAik: So this is my embedding key, and this is the value that has been generated.
Krish NAik: Value means time bidding, guys.
Krish NAik: How many of you are getting it?
Krish NAik: Because now, going forward, the catcher implementation will always take… just think about, if you remove catcher, the function will be much smaller and easier to understand, but when you are working with catcher, at every point of time, you need to do it. Because we have a document catcher implementation, as well as a query response catcher implementation.
Krish NAik: So, if, first of all, the condition is you have to check whether the catcher is available. If the catcher is available, you have to pick from the catcher. If the catcher is not available, then generate the embeddings, then again, put it into catcher.
Krish NAik: So that's why that catchy, catchy, catchy, everywhere catchy will come.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, Nabudes Sharma is telling, why not storing in VectorDB? Nabodesh Sarma, this is a function, generate embedding. Once the embeddings are generated, then only I will push it into VectorDB. So, the purpose of this embedding is… the purpose of this function is to generate the embeddings.
Krish NAik: We will come to that, but at a later stage.
Krish NAik: shouldn't we do something like an interceptor to have a centralized code for catching?
Krish NAik: Okay, centralized code for catch A, just think about, but in your core implementation, you have to keep it, no? Otherwise, how are you doing the check for embeddings?
Krish NAik: Because in your actual implementation, you have to keep that
Krish NAik: catchy implementation. Otherwise, how we will do the check, Muttasan?
Krish NAik: Because your check needs to be done. That's why this if-as-else condition just for catch.
Krish NAik: Call will happen to the interceptor.
Krish NAik: Alright, if you really think for Cache, if you want a catching scene, my main implementation of CatchA is here.
Krish NAik: This is the catcher service that I have.
Krish NAik: But for this particular catching service, I'm calling my all major catching functions through that.
Krish NAik: So this is the main catching service that I have, Modus.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why. So, if you think about… I can add more functions, but a few level of code, probably, I feel like few lines of code I can decrease. But again, with respect to my embedding generation, first of all, I need to have to check that particular condition.
Krish NAik: Alright, guys.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, the embedding check. If embedding is not available, generate the embeddings.
Krish NAik: the embeddings are generated again saved into Catcher, with individual keys for everyone.
Krish NAik: And finally, this logger.debug. Here, I kept it because, actually, I felt that I was getting some error, so in some cases, I have not kept only the debug information, but like, only the info level, rather than the debug level information also, I kept it.
Krish NAik: Now, during the embedding, so the usage info, the prompt tokens, total tokens, model, catch ahead, so these are all the, usage-level information that I'm saving it in a key.
Krish NAik: Now, I'm looking for an attribute, if it is available. So, generally, if the catcher hit or misses. So, these two things are my major. I can say, keys that will be returned even in your response.
Krish NAik: every point of time, in every catcher responses, whenever you will see that catcher hit, like, true or false condition, that I'll be maintaining it.
Krish NAik: Finally, the embeddings will be returned, and these embeddings, I'll be using it in the next step. So, two things that I'm returning, embeddings with
Krish NAik: Usage info. From the usage info, I can understand that, whether it hit my catcher or not. So that condition, is true or not. So simply, like, based on these two cases, you can make it true or false also. But catcher hit true, catcher miss. So, both of them, I have a boolean.
Krish NAik: Alright, finally, once the embeddings are generated, again, an exception condition, if there is some issue with respect to OpenAI package, and finally, return the embeddings.
Krish NAik: Okay, hit 0 means it's 100% catch a hit, so this is the final else logic, if, the… it gets hit from the catcher.
Krish NAik: Sanket is asking, what if the catcher misses? If the catcher misses this one, no. Generate the embeddings for uncatch text.
Krish NAik: Kache misses mean un-cache, sankh.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is the… it will generate the embeddings in that case.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, it will pick up from British.
Krish NAik: Aniroth, you can apply a debugger and you can do that.
Krish NAik: If you want, later on, you can put some breakpoints, and you can do the testing in that.
Krish NAik: Alright, because right now, when you have much more amount of code, my main focus will be the core functionality, rather than looking into everyone. If I start debugging this piece of code, it will take more than two classes for me.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now comes the next level.
Krish NAik: Okay, no catches available, so automatically my client.embitting same offering. So, two levels of embedding calls that I have, one much more from the chunk perspective, one much more from the, like, query perspective, because embedding needs to be done for both the cases. One is your
Krish NAik: query, one for your chance, because here, manually, you need to do it, as we are not working with LanChain or any others.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes, generating embedding for a single text, text field to embed, this function that I'll be actually using it when, during my.
Krish NAik: I can say query. Whenever I'll be passing the query in my VectorTV operations, then I'll be passing it. So this service is only to generate the embeddings. In actual line of code, if you want to do it, it's only 4 lines of code.
Krish NAik: But if you do so many integrations, logging, cache, it becomes. But actually, if I say that.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the only implementation in your init that you need. If you're not working with Cache, it becomes much easier. So, the core implementation is based on only these three nice of codes.
Krish NAik: Where, yes, this is the meme.
Krish NAik: Because using this, you can generate the embedding, as simple as that. If you are implementing so much of error handling, logging, the piece of code becomes much more bigger.
Krish NAik: But your core logic, the actual function, this is only one line of code.
Krish NAik: Okay, this is the main one-liner. Other than that, rest of the things are pretty much catcher handling, error handling, logger handling. Because of that, the code becomes much more bigger.
Krish NAik: You have to understand.
Krish NAik: Yes, generally for query embedding, I can directly use that generate single embedding. Okay, so this is the function that I can directly use.
Krish NAik: And the get the embedding dimension, already this is returned, I pass it, so I know that every point of time during the generation, it will use the 1536 dimension.
Krish NAik: So, once my embeddings are generated, what is the next step?
Krish NAik: VectorDB?
Krish NAik: So, let's come to our vector TV service. Now, for our vector TV, what I'll be using? Pinecone.
Krish NAik: So, two specifications that comes. Okay, one, I am using gRPC here. You can use the core Pinecone package, but I feel that gRPC is much more optimized, so I feel that it's better to work better. Now, when you are working with gRPC, then the serverless state that needs to be imported.
Krish NAik: Now, Josephine, why don't we modularize? We have login exception handling separately.
Krish NAik: Alright, that I can do, probably, if you want. I have not added that custom exception. So, generally, if you look into, I had that implementation plan.
Krish NAik: So, config.py in the usage. I've not created any custom validations right now. I've kept this. Later on, I can pass certain things, so that the core becomes much more lesser.
Krish NAik: But at least in some file, that main code will be there. Okay, so Josephine, you can do that. There is no restriction in that. Okay, in your separate, just to handle your errors or exceptions, I can do that. Probably in the next class, I can show you. But again, with respect to catching, at least you have to add
Krish NAik: The number of, lines… For sure, 10 to 15 lines in every 5…
Krish NAik: Or I can say more than that, 30 lines that might be reduced.
Krish NAik: Alright, but yes, custom classes. If you're even doing that custom implementation, then also you need to import that implementation there, Josephine. So, I feel that same one.
Krish NAik: Probably a few lines of code that can be reduced, but again, I feel that even you need to input it there, so not a major change that will do the reduction with respect to the code.
Krish NAik: Alright, now… what I was talking about, our VectorDB service.
Krish NAik: Now, here, my pinecone initialization. So, for our pinecone initialization.
Krish NAik: What is the first thing? So, my Pinecode settings, my API key environment indexing.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, this… the first one inside my constructor, I have kept it. After the constructor, first of all, I need to connect it with the index. So this is… so you are making your connection to your…
Krish NAik: Pinecone index that you have created.
Krish NAik: So, if the index is available, it's great, otherwise it will be creating the index. So, this is a check. If the index is available, if the index is not available, simply create an index.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this is handed in your course, so don't think about if you have not created an intense, it won't work. So, automatically, it will be created.
Krish NAik: Once the index is available, the next step comes as adding the documents. So, this is the place. Now, to add documents, what are the things that you need?
Krish NAik: So chunk, embedding… okay. Now, why this chunk information? Because, whenever you are doing the embedding, you need that core chunk information. Okay, so that's why.
Krish NAik: Then comes your file name, and then comes your namespace. So right here, I'm using the default namespace. Otherwise, you can create your own custom namespace as also.
Krish NAik: So, if you look into namespaces, okay, so I'm using the default one, but you can create your own namespaces. So generally, if you have something like a hierarchy, okay, so, for example, if you're, working, like, multiple type of documents, financial, HR, ops, and something like that, to try to maintain different
Krish NAik: Namespaces.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in… here, you can do. So, in Pinecone, two level of, differentiation that you can do. First.
Krish NAik: Index level, you can create separate indexes, but always creating indexes is not a good practice. Rather than the second level of differentiation, it means that you can differentiate among the namespaces. So, your search becomes much more optimized.
Krish NAik: And then, finally, on top of metadata. So, like.
Krish NAik: step by step, first you go into the index, so the index selection, once the index is selected, then comes your namespace selection. Once the namespace is selected, then through metadata, you can apply the filters.
Krish NAik: Okay, so 3 levels always, understand. So, 3 levels of filtering that you can apply it in your logic.
Krish NAik: Mitesh is asking, SQL versus RAC can be two namespaces. Okay, yes, if you're working with that.
Krish NAik: Because right now, I don't have any SQL data, but if you really think about, okay, simple, like, if you have multiple departments, and that way you can place your name spaces, or if you feel that the information is much more confidential, if not pre-shared, then try to, create different indexes for those, different departments.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Now, to add the documents, first of all, I need to connect with the index, so already I've defined that particular function, then I'll be having a checking. If length of the chunks is not equal to length of the index, so simply a value error. Now, for everything, if you start creating, I feel that the amount of your
Krish NAik: error handling will be very, very big, because for everything, you have one custom condition. You can keep it, but later on, going through… because if I just try to discuss only a file with respect to error handling, I feel it's much more… less relevant, but for production, it's a much better approach.
Krish NAik: Now, the next step is preparing the vectors for upsert. So, generally, you can think about uploading your vectors. Okay, so in some places, it's called an insert operation, in some places, it's called an upset. So, upload plus insert.
Krish NAik: Because uploading the documents to cloud and then inserting them into index, so that's why the term upset has been used.
Krish NAik: Now, let's go… we'll be performing a for loop operation on top of everyone. And now, with every chunk, this is the metadata that I have appended in Pinecone Index.
Krish NAik: And finally, the vectors that I have selected, one by one, within this for loop, you have this vector2 offset, so one by one, everything that you can upload. Now, the maximum batch size that I have passed is 100. Don't think if you pass 10,000, it will work as 10,000. There are batch limits and Banco in every vector databases in the cloud.
Krish NAik: Okay, so always try to go with lesser batches, try to process it in, like, 50, 100,
Krish NAik: These are optimal months that I feel.
Krish NAik: Generally, in Quadrant, I have seen that, it's supposed till 512. If I cross that 512 bath size, okay, then again, I have to do a time.ke for every API call that I make to the quadrant cluster. Similarly, in Pinecone also, if you make this 1000,
Krish NAik: Okay, and you might get an error, so always try to go with lower batch sizes, at least less than 512.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, in the next step, Hmm…
Krish NAik: Okay, now, see, my document is uploaded, not my document, my vectors are uploaded in the vector space. If the vectors are available, what is the next step? Search.
Krish NAik: So, directly from Pinecone, I need to connect to the index and see. This is the index query. This implementation I have taken directly upon Pinecone. Simple cosine similarity.
Krish NAik: implementation.
Krish NAik: Now, Saurav, what am I saying, if we have embedded, let's say, 100 documents as historical data, now if the new document is to be uploaded, then do we need to run the embedding model? If the documents are exactly the same, why we'll be running the embedding model, sir?
Krish NAik: If the document is 100% exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Okay, then you don't need to run the embedding model. If… but you need to save those embeddings somewhere for that particular document, the embedding as well as the channel, like in the structure.
Krish NAik: Okay, so yesterday I showed you that data. If you have… if you are saving this information document-wise, then you don't need to do that.
Krish NAik: Oh my god.
Krish NAik: How to get the similarity score? How to get… it means that when you will perform the search, it is based on similarity score. This search that I'm doing, this is the cosine similarity implementation on Python.
Krish NAik: Then, okay, E237i was having Pingone vectors already, like, creating new absurd, it was not allowing only
Krish NAik: allow deleting. I don't know if the free version of…
Krish NAik: Pinecone, I think… what is the limit? I think it's close to 2GB.
Krish NAik: Because even I have not tested it out.
Krish NAik: But I think it's close to 2 GB or something like that.
Krish NAik: Re-rankers, I'll be talking about Mitesh when I'll be discussing hybrid rack. This is not an hybrid rack project, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, this is the search part, one of the search results you were getting. So here, I've not added any type of metadata filtering or anything, so as you can see, this is a simple trial logic, if this works or not.
Krish NAik: If this was fine, format the result with respect to the chunk, because I need to throw the result in the retrieval. So this will be the actual output of the retriever that you can look in.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes get index stats, so get stats about the Pinecone Index, if you want, really, like, what type of namespace. If you remember, you had that, you can create specific route.
Krish NAik: Just to check that everything is up or not. I need these stats because I was doing an initialization of all the services. So because of that, I need all the stats.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, again, now, delete by file name. Now, this particular option is there if you want to delete all the vectors with respect to a certain file name, so that particular option, I have kept it. Now comes delete all the vectors.
Krish NAik: Now, this implementation, I think I added a day before yesterday, because I feel that when multiple times you are uploading, repeated vectors can be there. So, if you want to do it, it's a simple implementation that I have kept it, and even available in FastAPI route.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the implementation. Now, always remember, these implementations will change. Why? Because this is based on Pinecone package. If you change to Quadrant, if you change to Milverse, all this implementation will change.
Krish NAik: I hope everybody understands that. Yes or no. But if you are working with LandChain, this implementation won't change.
Krish NAik: How many of you get that I am trying to say?
Krish NAik: If you are working with Lama Indeed for every module, okay, it means that it becomes much easier for a developer if you want to directly switch from here to there. But generally, in production, we don't switch from this DB to this DB from this DB.
Krish NAik: For your learning, it's good. But actually, in production, you have to make the decision, okay, now this is a DB, so that's why
Krish NAik: And this is your finance selection. So I'm telling you, majorly, like, all the services, these are much more packaged, because I've taken the decision that I will go with this.
Krish NAik: That's why. So all these implementations will change. If you change Pinecone, if you just think about, okay, Paul, can I switch to Quadrant? I have to say that this entire vectorService.py code needs to be updated.
Krish NAik: But in Langchain, it's much lesser implementation of code that you need to work with.
Krish NAik: So, can we check? Yes, you can create a file version system if you want to do that. That is nothing related to AI, but you can create your own file version system to have a chain.
Krish NAik: Alright, then comes delete the vectors. Now, the core implementation of vector service is done.
Krish NAik: Now, the next thing, once the vector service is done, so what is the next step?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: What is the next step?
Krish NAik: Rabin Pal is telling Retrieval.
Krish NAik: No. So, generally, like, after the vector service, by default, yes, your retrieval comes.
Krish NAik: Now, if I go into… but you have to understand, my retrieval was there in the vector service. How many of you understood that? Because many people wrote retrieval.
Krish NAik: So that's why…
Krish NAik: I am doing… no, no, no, re-ranking and others. Right now, I'm not talking from that perspective. It will be in hybrid rank when I say hybrid plus re-rankers, probably in the next project that I'll be doing. In this project, there is no re-ranking or any other thing.
Krish NAik: Step by step, because in the next project, I'm not going to implement so much of logging or catch anything. I will just remove all those surveys, and I will focus on only the core rack function.
Krish NAik: In every project, if I try to add it, it will become very, very big.
Krish NAik: All right.
Krish NAik: Okay, so in this service, my retrieval is available. Please let me know how many of you get it.
Krish NAik: How many of you get it? In my current vectorService.py, The retrieval is automatically there.
Krish NAik: I showed you.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Alright, then a few other services that I have.
Krish NAik: One is after your… so, one is the storage backend service that I have. Let's talk about this, because if you remember, I need a decision to save it in my local machine, or in…
Krish NAik: Where? Or in web? Quickly tell me.
Krish NAik: S3. Okay, so because of that, I have to… one is the storage backend, and the S3 storage implementation, because in S3, I need all those Boto Photo service, it means that Bhoto 3 and that, so that piece of implementation, if you look into Boto 3. But for our storage backend, if I'm making it local, I really don't need to do the implementation.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, check if all the catches document exists. So, as you can see, so few conditional checks that I have kept it, because when I'm saving it, just think in my local laws, what is the first level of saving that I have done?
Krish NAik: Can you see this hash?
Krish NAik: So that's why def exists or not. Check if the catcher files exist for a certain document.
Krish NAik: Then comes save the document.
Krish NAik: Okay, right now, everything, if you look into, later on, that I can use them, so pretty much blank functions.
Krish NAik: Okay, because I was thinking about doing, but as I have not done my local implementation, my core
Krish NAik: focus one on S3, so my main one, but these are pretty much blank holders that have kept it.
Krish NAik: How many of you got? What I have done? This is a blank folder implementation. If we are selecting the backend. Now, later on, I can change and I can simply pass, like, wherever I want to do it.
Krish NAik: So, pretty much, this is a simple boilerplate that you guys can use it.
Krish NAik: Yes, like a simple interface, I can say, but very, very simple objective.
Krish NAik: Now, this storage backend that I have, you will see that if I go to my… here.
Krish NAik: Can you see I'm calling here that particular boilerplate, the interface that I have defined?
Krish NAik: Pretty much abstract classes, yes. This is quite widely used in LCL, yes, correct, in LANCH and LC, it is.
Krish NAik: Now, I know that I need to call them. So, first of all, my class S3. So, as you can see, my Boto, so I know from my command line. And these are the documents that… now, see, this is the file structure that I've defined, like PDF, inside that I'll be having the document hash.
Krish NAik: Then, all the documents.
Krish NAik: Just wait, okay, just give me.
Krish NAik: 5 minutes I've been speaking, and it's pretty much dried.
Krish NAik: Alright, now this is the structure for organizing your documents in S3.
Krish NAik: Now in the next step. So, first of all, we have to select what are the regions that I have selected, what is the name of the bucket. So, those configurations, then we have to connect it to mine, so configure 423 with retry logic. If it fails, so maximum 3 retries that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, then, so go to3.client. Now, this is the actual one. This code is responsible.
Krish NAik: To make the connection, so right now.
Krish NAik: You should have the S3 access, that is also important. If you don't have the access for this particular user, then it won't be connected. Then we will be doing this validated bucket. What is the purpose of doing this particular validation?
Krish NAik: If the bucket exists or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, but in this validation, we are just checking that if the bucket exists or not.
Krish NAik: If the bucket does not exist, then what to do?
Krish NAik: you can create the bucket, so that logic, you can add it here. I feel that it should be there, but in my case, simply, like, you need to have that S3 full access, then you can add that functionality here. If the bucket is missing, simply create it.
Krish NAik: Now, the next thing that comes is generating the S3P with the folder structure.
Krish NAik: Now, I planned about this folder structure, so you have to really plan what type of folder structure that you want.
Krish NAik: Based on that. Because the first is the extension, then comes your hash.
Krish NAik: the document has… that has been generated, and within that, you will be saving your original document shown metadata, just like
Krish NAik: our local data folder that I have shown you multiple times.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, then the next thing is, you can look into the objects of a bucket, so for that object exists or not.
Krish NAik: Okay, so why this exists and exists? I have kept it everywhere. Can anybody tell me?
Krish NAik: This is a check that all the four files for a certain document, when you are uploading, they are available or not.
Krish NAik: It's a check, simply that I have added.
Krish NAik: Now, first of all, whenever you open a bucket, I think everybody knows, the first thing, you can look into the objects. Yes or no? So that's why that an object check is required.
Krish NAik: just think about if something not got uploaded, okay, and if there are no objects, so I can say that pretty much the bucket is blank.
Krish NAik: Then comes, within the next object, again, one more loop where we'll be actually checking that, yes, these files are available on…
Krish NAik: So, within… because I have my PDF, inside that I have my hash. Within that hash, I have the file type. So, all the file exist or not. So, again, a condition.
Krish NAik: Finally comes uploading. So, this is where, you can upload your document to… so this is the main function, saving the document to a screen.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now, one is your main actual document, the PDF or the text file, then comes… for that PDF file, what are the chunks, as you can see here, based on the structure, then comes your embedding file, then comes, in the next step.
Krish NAik: Your metadata file.
Krish NAik: Okay?
Krish NAik: Now, this is the main thing, where you are actually doing the save operation.
Krish NAik: And everywhere, you have to maintain the document ID. That is very, very important.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright, Madhasar, you can drop, okay, later on, because I don't think I can complete all this today. It's already going to be 12, okay? So, in the next class also, we'll be… we can do the little bit discussion, and then we can, discuss the actual deployment.
Krish NAik: Alright. Now, once you have saved the metadata.
Krish NAik: Then in the next step is now, loading the chunks.
Krish NAik: Okay, so with respect to, loading the chunks, when you need this, can anybody tell me? Loading of chunks is required when?
Krish NAik: Quickly tell me in the chat, when you need to load the channels.
Krish NAik: Guys, quickly tell me, cache, correct.
Krish NAik: This is not reddish, okay? So directly, you can change. Document is large, doesn't matter. In S3, you can put anything on.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, loading the chunks and loading the embeddings, it means that when you fail that, okay, the hash is matching. In that case, actually, you can do that load chunks, load metadata, so that particular condition that I have. Now, if you want to delete everything, if you remember, I have a fast API route.
Krish NAik: to delete everything from S3. So, for that, delete all these four types.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So, here specifically, you can pass the key if you want to delete a certain item. Okay, if you want to delete everything, then delete all. So both of these functions are actually included in the FastAPI route.
Krish NAik: Now, PG Nation, if you want to apply now, again, this is an optional approach. You can apply ACL versioning and other things, some S3 features that comes from AWS.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you want to delete the object, so generally, like, after 90 days or after 120 days, if something is not getting reused, I might put it into S3 Glacier. How many of you know about Esri Glacier?
Krish NAik: It's cheaper as compared to a screen.
Krish NAik: Yes?
Krish NAik: Because after a certain point of time, when you feel that, really, the data doesn't matter to us, then actually you can put it there, okay, in circulation. It's much more cheaper as compared, so it's a better approach.
Krish NAik: Alright, once you have this, then comes one function is there just to show you the list documents.
Krish NAik: Then getting the S3 catches stats, okay, the S3 information.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, that's right, because these are much more from Bhuto implementation. If you have worked with Boto, otherwise, like, this will be good for…
Krish NAik: That's… So I have added everywhere a lot of phone, I can say.
Krish NAik: comments. So, these are called as… I forgot that word. What is called? Doc strings.
Krish NAik: For every function.
Krish NAik: Now, this is my S3 storage. Now, after my S3 storage.
Krish NAik: What other service that is, remaining?
Krish NAik: Then you have this,
Krish NAik: The RAG service, okay, so let's talk about, little bit about the RAG service also.
Krish NAik: Because this local storage and S3 storage, it means that, see, local storage means everything in the local.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this file is, it's also pretty much very, very similar to our S3 backend. If you want to save something in the local, so you know that I have that particular flag variable in my config, where you write S3 or local. So, based on that flag, it will be invoked here.
Krish NAik: Now, similar in it?
Krish NAik: in my unit, majorly, the catcher directory. Okay, so right now, as you know, so… first of all, I will be saving, like, in where I want to save it. So, directory… so my catcher directory needs to be taken. So, here, it's actually catch it underscore chunks. Within that, I'm saving all the information.
Krish NAik: Now, this condition of catcher directory, or your upload directory, okay, now this comes under here, div catcher directory. Can you see? This is actually a property for lambda.
Krish NAik: But right now, you can see the return type. If the environment is local, like data slash catch at chunks. Okay, which is data slash catch at chunks.
Krish NAik: Always look into the folder structure, a very similar structure that you can look here. So everything will be uploaded into, or basically uploaded… it's not upload, it will be saved into this particular local storage.
Krish NAik: All right. Then, if the directory is not available, create the directory, that's why MKDR I have.
Krish NAik: Then, getting the folder path for a document, okay, so that's why self.catcher directory that I have selected, slash the document ID, which is basically the…
Krish NAik: SHA256 hash. Similarly, I will check that whether all the catch-up file exist or not for a certain document, a simple check by looking into the existing files.
Krish NAik: Then comes saving all those documents. A very similar approach, just like S3, if you look into the functions are exactly the same. Then finally comes saving your chunks into your local, saving your embedding, saving your metadata.
Krish NAik: Okay, so every implementation is there.
Krish NAik: Then, once the metadata is finally saved, then comes loading. It means that if catcher hits into the picture, then these load chunks and this other implementations will come. So, the main purpose of loading is for those catcher servers.
Krish NAik: Load chunks, load emittings, load metadata, okay? And finally, if you want to delete something, so for that also, I have a specific route, slash delete. Okay, and finally, list document, if you remember, this particular service also, I had to list the total number of documents.
Krish NAik: Okay, so whenever you are uploading. So, few routes.
Krish NAik: And get storage statistics if you want the total number of documents, total file, total image size, this is returned in the API response.
Krish NAik: And… I think this is returned here. Okay, alright.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the output JSON format, which is written in your API, if the storage is bad.
Krish NAik: So, these two files of local storage backend, and your, I can say.
Krish NAik: S3 storage. They are exactly the same, only
Krish NAik: One is in cloud, one is in local.
Krish NAik: So, it totally depends upon you where you want to dump your embeddings metadata. So, based on that, in the configuration, you have to select the flag building.
Krish NAik: Now, the next service, let's talk about the RAG service a little bit, because the RAG service is your main one, where you have to do the
Krish NAik: LLM Generation.
Krish NAik: Okay, now for the LLM generation, again, which package is required?
Krish NAik: Yes, guys, which package is required?
Krish NAik: In our case, it's OpenAI. So, simply, you can see that async OpenAI is there, okay? So, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Now, to do the LLM response generation, so yes, OpenAI will be used with that.
Krish NAik: the vector service and the embedding services, few things that I need.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, let's initialize.
Krish NAik: All are core important things, okay? So, for example, the OpenAI API key, the embedding service, through embedding service, again, I am passing the API key. I know both of the API keys are exactly the same.
Krish NAik: Then comes your query catcher service. Now, this implementation is also required, because here also we'll be looking into the catcher. Why we'll be looking into the catcher? Because the query part, okay, I'm putting it in the catcher, but as well as the response of the LLM, that also I'm putting it in the catcher.
Krish NAik: Okay? For that purpose. And right now, this catcher is much more about the embedding catcher. Okay, your query catcher. This is not about your response one, because for response one, again, I have to, like, initialize it later on, and other function I've done it.
Krish NAik: So, embedding service, then comes your vector service initialization, your LLM client, so here I'm directly calling my async OpenAI, and the API key that I have passed.
Krish NAik: Then comes your query catcher service. Okay, now this is the catcher service. Query catcher service is for your query and response model. It means for SQL as well as for the RAM. Both will be catcher. So that also I have, called it.
Krish NAik: Then comes your LLM configuration, so here I have used GPT-4 Turbo Preview. You can switch to other LLMs, and you can have it checked.
Krish NAik: Aniru, these tellings are unable to see, yes, right now, I think I have switched on the cam, okay? Just wait, I will switch on it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so now, we have to generate the answer. Generate the answer, so for that, what I need.
Krish NAik: So, first of all, few information, with respect to mean or retrieval, okay, it's my vector DB, because as I have initialized my vector service, so for that, there I'm using the namespace, then comes your top K result.
Krish NAik: Included sources, so if you want to look into that sources, so that's why, by default, the Boolean, I have kept it as true. Later on, you can switch it. Now, the return type will be a dictionary, because generally, I work with dictionary, it's much easier to convert a diction into a JSON object.
Krish NAik: Oh my god.
Krish NAik: Now, again, all the conditions for catcher will come first.
Krish NAik: Because before generating the answer, you need to look into your catcher.
Krish NAik: Okay, if it hits into the catcher, fine. From the catcher, you will pick up the result and you will show it.
Krish NAik: Yes or no?
Krish NAik: That's why we have to check the catcher first.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: Now, generating the embedding for the query, so for sure, like, this particular implementation is required, which I have taken from generate embedding. So, if you really look into this generate embedding, so for your query also, you need it.
Krish NAik: Okay, and based on that query only, on top of that, you can perform the search service.
Krish NAik: So that's why, we are generating the query embeddings, so that's why I'm telling query embeddings. Very specifically, it means that the user will pass the query, that query I'm doing the embedding for it. And then I am initializing my search service. If you remember the search, this search, I'm calling it from here, dev search from my vector service.
Krish NAik: Once I initialize this, then I'll be getting my result, which is basically the search result. Now, search result chunks, so I'm actually looking only for the chance to show you. So, first of all, the question that I have asked, which becomes a query. Then, if…
Krish NAik: If there are no chunks available. So, if not chunk, it means that in the search, if there is no chunk.
Krish NAik: Okay, now this will be returned. I don't have enough information.
Krish NAik: So that's why this particular condition, if the chunks are returned, if the condition is true, then we'll be building up the context. Then comes create prompt.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, generally, your question and context comes together.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this create prompt again that I have inside the rack service, which is below, actually.
Krish NAik: that I am calling.
Krish NAik: So, always, you can just, click exactly on which function, that I'm calling. So…
Krish NAik: These are much more private functions, that's why I kept it as underscore. So, one is build context. This is the build context part. When you are building the context, what do you need, guys?
Krish NAik: what you need. When you are building the context, it means that format.union.join operation.uto for every chunk.
Krish NAik: Did you get that?
Krish NAik: Because in Langshan directly by using a function, you do it.
Krish NAik: Okay, but here, very, specifically, that I'm building the context form.
Krish NAik: Alright, now once your context is available, now in the next step.
Krish NAik: is creating the prompt, because this is the final prompt. In the prompt, what I will be passing, the core context with the user question, if you will see.
Krish NAik: This is to type. So, you can look into a pretty much simple prompt that I have passed. If you are a helpful assistant, answer the question based on the provided. If the contact doesn't, so pretty much a simple prompt that I have added. Now, this prompt, I'll be sending it to the LLM.
Krish NAik: Alright, now comes create prompt, okay. Now, I'm, invoking the chat completion API. Whenever you are directly working with OpenAI, I think everybody knows about chat completion.
Krish NAik: This is the actual API that you call it.
Krish NAik: I think majorly, every LLM, you have this chat completion.
Krish NAik: Yes. Now, so this is the actual message, role system content that I have passed. Role user and content is basically the prompt that I will be passing, through which I have built. You can see this prompt variable, this I have passed it here.
Krish NAik: Simply.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then a few configurations with respect to the LLMs, the temperature, and the max number of tokens.
Krish NAik: That I have selected. Once I do the invoking of that API, I'll be getting the results. Now, from the LLM usage, you can get the prompt tokens, the completion tokens, and the total tokens.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the response type of any type of LLM data you try to invoke. So, you can actually get your cost, you can actually calculate the total cost for a certain call.
Krish NAik: So, cost tracking can be enabled even through OPEC.
Krish NAik: Okay, so generally, in any observability tool, you can actually get all this information, and you can actually do the cost tracking for every call that you make.
Krish NAik: Now comes, finally, our final combined usage. Okay, so where the embedding, as well as the LLM, okay, now this is my combined usage, where my embedding tokens, LLM prompt tokens, completion tokens, everything that I'll be getting.
Krish NAik: Now, generally, if you're doing a cost tracking, I feel that this implementation is much easier. You should do, otherwise, simply, you can skip this. Okay, it's just more added level of functionality if you want to do a tracking for every LLM call that you make.
Krish NAik: Now, the final result will be in this particular format. Your question, your answer, that I'll be getting it from the LLM. That's why the dev generate answer that I have.
Krish NAik: Okay, and the chunks which are used, the length of the chunks, okay, so in our case, like, 3 chunks, which is the top K that will be used. Now, the actual model response to which model has been used, and this combined usage.
Krish NAik: Okay, now you can see here, this I'm doing only for OPEC.
Krish NAik: Okay? I'm doing only for PIC. Otherwise, if I'm not doing any observability, simply these implementations, I would be keeping it in my pool. This is only for cost tracking.
Krish NAik: Because embeddings comes with a cost.
Krish NAik: LLMs comes with a cost, because both the models are different.
Krish NAik: So that's why, previously here, prompt completion. So, these are all related to LLM. Here, I have combined the embedding as well as that.
Krish NAik: Alright, now, that particular Boolean condition, if I'm making it true, like, if include sources, it means that your top K, if you want to show it in the results, so format. So, for that, I need to do the formatting. Again, for that, I have a separate function. Just to show you in the JSON response.
Krish NAik: Now, catcher the result. Now, as if the catcher misses all this information, I'll be putting it where? In the
Krish NAik: Red is catching.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, if you're… if you are doing all these operations.
Krish NAik: It means that I have the final result. If I have the final result, where I'll be putting it in the ready schedule.
Krish NAik: Perfect.
Krish NAik: Now, simply, my final, exception. If something fails here, the exception will come.
Krish NAik: Now, coming to my custom function, one is to build the context. If you really look into, I'm looping over, and finally, all those context parts that I'm appending in a single list.
Krish NAik: So, simply, like, the idea is to iterate over all the chunks and add that information to build our final context that I'll be passing it within the prompt. So, finally, you can see context part.append, so for every chunk information, I am passing it here.
Krish NAik: the actual chunk of data. Then comes creating the prompt, a simple prompt that I have.
Krish NAik: Then, getting the similar chunks, So far, similar chunks.
Krish NAik: what do you have to do? You have to use the vector service. It means that when you are performing this operation, you have to first invoke your generate single embedding. Now, this is your query embedding.
Krish NAik: A simple implementation, as you can see.
Krish NAik: And on top of that, directly, I'm applying the vector search. Now, this implementation is much easier whenever you are working with embedding, rather than going through our older implementation. So, directly, that I have called it here.
Krish NAik: So where is my emitting part?
Krish NAik: Okay, so… this one. My embedding service. So, generate the query embeddings with usage tracking. But this time, there is no usage tracking in that.
Krish NAik: So that's why, like, it totally depends upon what type of implementation you want to picket in your port.
Krish NAik: Alright, so once I'll be getting my final vector results, so this is a simple try block. If everything works good, the results will be returned.
Krish NAik: Okay, and finally, if anything fails, fail to retrieve leveled chunks.
Krish NAik: Now, this is the core RAT service that I have, so, with this implementation. And finally, I think I have the…
Krish NAik: This service that I have, Okay. Query catcher service.
Krish NAik: Alright, I think query catcher I will be discussing in the next, because already I have discussed so many files. Okay, little bit of overwhelming it can be with respect to the implementation, so let's do it Saturday.
Krish NAik: Because I know, like, next week also we'll be discussing this project only.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let's keep it till this point. I have my catcher service, I'll be discussing, catcherservice.py.
Krish NAik: and query cache service, these two files are remaining. Then SQL service is also remaining, which is the VANA.ai integration that I have done. Alright, fine. So, providing 3 services for the next class, let's keep it.
Krish NAik: Sankat is telling, but next week, yes, I will be on team vacation these weekdays, not weekend.
Krish NAik: Okay, my flight is on Friday to Bangalore, so I know that I will return to Bangalore on
Krish NAik: Friday, but if something happens, like, really, when we go for vacations, it can be one or two day extensions.
Krish NAik: Because I know that if we do the cancellation, it means all batches will be done.
Krish NAik: Okay, so that's why.
Krish NAik: And I think that the new batch for the project, so probably, like, I have the tickets for Friday return, but if something happens that I'm telling, like, one day extension.
Krish NAik: it might happen. So, let's do the discussion of the REST3 services in the next class.
Krish NAik: Okay, so one small request, can you please add, the order of the files, numbering 01, so that you're easy to follow?
Krish NAik: What's the ordering? Here, I cannot make ordering. You can look into your mainapp.py, where I'm making all those calls.
Krish NAik: This is the actual file that you need to look into. SK.
Krish NAik: This is much more initial, because service-related calls directly. So, the structure device in which API view? So, this is the mean.py. Till now, I have not discussed the mean.py.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there you will get the structure. Sand the class is done for today.
Krish NAik: Okay, I mean, which month? Probably, like, first week of April is my target, let's see. It can be, like, second week also.
Krish NAik: a third week also, but an estimated time. If I cancel some classes in between, so for sure it will be a little bit late.
Krish NAik: Alright, something, okay… Because in the next class, with respect to the sequence, About the project batch…
Krish NAik: Alright, can we get the timeline for this batch?
Krish NAik: I told you, no, the timeline. It will be, like, uplay. If you look into Notion, check your Notion, because in Notion, a rough estimated timeline that I have kept it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so I know that, because once this project is completed, then I will start with the project 3, which is your advanced rack project, or basically that hybrid rack, re-ranking everything, that after this, I will directly start, then I will discuss HTAC. Once H-Tag is done, then I will start with agents.
Krish NAik: your Langra part, okay? So…
Krish NAik: Any coupons? You can call the counseling team. Okay, I think you guys already have the number as you have taken that enrollment of this batch.
Krish NAik: Ishaan, or…
Krish NAik: The IAS will be there, okay, so those guys can help you out. Hassil, please provide the notion, like, Hassan Khan, are you a new…
Krish NAik: Student? Hasan?
Krish NAik: Because this link, I'm sharing it, for the past 3 months, again, people are asking.
Krish NAik: I think right now, if I told you it's selling 9K.
Krish NAik: Okay, later on, I think, once…
Krish NAik: Initially, I think for starting 500 students, we have, like, 9K.
Krish NAik: But, till 1000 for our internal BAC students, it will. But I know that we are planning to increase the cycle.
Krish NAik: Because all the other competitors in the market, they are charging a lot.
Krish NAik: That's right. So, Mitesh, any ideas on the schedule for the weekend class for projects? Any idea on the schedule? Night?
Krish NAik: I think it'll be around, after 7pm or 8pm.
Krish NAik: So, like, rag batch, no conflict. Rag morning, project, it will be at night only. Weekends, only in weekends, yes.
Krish NAik: That is only weekend. And around 7pm, 7.30pm, 8 PM. Exact timing, I don't know.
Krish NAik: I know that it will be around 8pm, 8pm to 11pm, like, 3 hours, the project classes.
Krish NAik: For this project patch, okay, so don't get confused.
Krish NAik: No. No happier day. Simply, like, initially, because we know, like.
Krish NAik: Indian crowd that I know, like, what are the students' mentality.
Krish NAik: They will take, like, even, like, we were planning for one month, then actually, like, one of our core investors, he only told, like, in India, everybody, they will take their subscription, download all the code.
Krish NAik: Okay, and then gone. So that's why we didn't want that. So everything is right now handled.
Krish NAik: RAC 2.0 Batchman Scott,
Krish NAik: See, guys, you don't need to worry about RAG 2.2, because that batch won't be for you. Your patch will be an advanced LLM and the RAC batch that I'll be launching. But I need to check my availability that when I can take that batch.
Krish NAik: Because my slot, morning slot, is done, but after 5 months or 6 months, I will be getting that UDS batch. So I know that RAG 2.0 will be in night, but that advanced batch that I'm planning only for you guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so let me see. It will be probably in between. Generally, for US students, it will be much tougher, because if I keep it in, afternoon in India.
Krish NAik: Okay, I know that in English it will be night, so…
Krish NAik: You need to plan for that. Let's see.
Krish NAik: Yes, that would mean VLM, LLM, okay, much more advanced, because…
Krish NAik: You think about on infrastructure, you might spend more than $50 to $100. That's all.
Krish NAik: Because when you are working with much more LLMs, VLLMs, you need a lot of info. So, I will be working with a lot of good info, like H100, B200, like, every hour for a practical, you might spend
Krish NAik: $10, not $20. So, that's why. Only specialized people who think, only those guys, only I will enroll. It's not like, for anybody, I will do the… open the enroll.
Krish NAik: I'm planning for a small, at least some type of test, or something like that, because it will be an experimental batch for
Krish NAik: Generally, we don't do it, but let's see if I can do it.
Krish NAik: Advanced LLM batch. See, guys, your batch will complete
Krish NAik: with that UTS, because my… both slots are booked. Like, at night also, I have batches. My batches will complete in the month of… if I take a tentative at least by 10th of April. After that, I will be taking a one-month break.
Krish NAik: like, complete holiday for one month, then I will come back. It means that the launch will be happening in the month of April, and the batch that will be starting, it will be from
Krish NAik: mean.
Krish NAik: like, the third week of May, or the fourth week of May. That is a rough estimation that I tell you.
Krish NAik: Well, I think both the batches of RAG and the advanced rag. Advanced RAG, little bit, see, I need to work on the content also. So for that, I need to take some time, because some level, because I'm not plant, like, AWS, SageMaker, or some custom solution, like Fast.api, it means that renting a GPU.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Krish NAik: So I really need to do that planning, so that's why I'll be taking one month break. In that one month, I will be planning.
Krish NAik: And then I will tell you guys.
Krish NAik: Okay, so probably I can keep some meetings just to discuss what are the things that we can plan.
Krish NAik: Because one month complete vacation, I will be in some other country, not in India. That's why. So I can keep some weekly meetings, whoever wants to that. We can have a detailed discussion, because that curriculum, 50% my input, 50% you can give your input.
Krish NAik: So that's why, actually, I've released that Google Form. Again, I will be sharing that Google Form going forward, so that whatever the things that you plan.
Krish NAik: Advanced Wagon LLM, really see rising, but I'm not sure, but at least it will be…
Krish NAik: My idea is that at least it will be close to More than $100?
Krish NAik: Less than $200, something in between.
Krish NAik: Okay? So, something in between you two.
Krish NAik: It's not like that, a lot, like, 50K, nothing like that, like, 100, 200 in between. What I have to suggest, for example, if there are only 10 students.
Krish NAik: Then, for sure, I won't be launching that batch.
Krish NAik: I… because for 10 students, I cannot do such a dedication, you have to understand.
Krish NAik: Okay, so… That's why I have to take the input from other agent batches, agent 1.0, 2.2, that's fine.
Krish NAik: Because I know I need very niche crowd, I don't need any generic crowd there, people who are actually doing development.
Krish NAik: Now, rather than in architects, not for 1 year or two years, at least, that you should be more than 2 years of experience. For them only, I'm opening that.
Krish NAik: But, again, because that batch only be, like, 3- 3-hours batch, it will be only 2 hours batch.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, only 2 hours.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Krish NAik: Google Form, I'll be sharing last class, I think few people have provided their inputs, but very few people have done it. Okay, just wait, if I can…
Krish NAik: Share it, I think, right? Why contact?
Krish NAik: Because in 2.0, I'll be removing a lot of parsers, actually. Okay, this is contact, sorry, not contact where is Kenya.
Krish NAik: You guys can also pass your inputs.
Krish NAik: Because once your course is done, then I think better if you pass your inputs, because few people have filled this form. I looked into the responses, like, I can see few people have done it. Again, LLM fine-tuning, metadata creation we'll be doing in this course only.
Krish NAik: MEM0 alright, Mem0 Paper AI, Gibson AI pretty much seems that MEM0 integration with respect to agents are… in this course only.
Krish NAik: Now, somebody's asking when, not really, like, when you're asking something, just be…
Krish NAik: Access control layer, retase, here I have done it.
Krish NAik: Okay, a few things are there, but let me just share the form, I think.
Krish NAik: shorten the URL copy, like, you guys… like, it's a continuous form, so you guys keep on adding your inputs. Later on, I'll be adding filters just to check.
Krish NAik: Always understand it only with respect to agents, because my main job is not with agents.
Krish NAik: Agents is not R&D, you have to understand. My main work is much more with respect to NLP, visual computing, LLLMs. Okay.
Krish NAik: I will be focusing on these topics. Agents is not my cup of tea, I really don't love agents so much, because at the end of the day, people say it agent and autonomous things, but I know at the end of the day, it's very much API-based executions and LLM-based.
Krish NAik: Okay, so there is not a lot of R&D. My focus is much more on R&D part.
Krish NAik: Because in syllabus, I don't love so much of things with respect to agents.
Krish NAik: I don't find it interesting, Moses.
Krish NAik: So you guys can pass your inputs, and then for our future patches, we can plan.
Krish NAik: Alright, so let me take some questions to the document screen…
Krish NAik: This is desktop 2 for me. The people who want, they can raise out.
Krish NAik: And participants, I can see a few hands are raised. Let's go with Abhishe.
Krish NAik: Deva Jyoti, Shrei, Rahul, everybody I have unlimited, so one by one, you guys can do it.
Abhishek: Hey, hi, Paul. Thanks, thanks for the class.
Abhishek: Just one, doubt I have, right? When we do… when we are doing the caching of the embedding, right? So, generally, the documents upload will be very huge, right? And then when we…
Abhishek: If we cache all these embeddings, so it will be costly as well, and we might not, cache each and every embedding, so how to plan that?
Abhishek: Think.
Krish NAik: See, a simple example that I can say, when you are working with radius, so let's take, in our example, it was taking 20KB.
Krish NAik: Now, just think about if you have 10 million vectors. Do that multiplication again, what will be the mean size that will be taking.
Krish NAik: Okay, now, what you can do, generally, what will do this Redis, okay, so there is a TTA, like, time to live.
Krish NAik: I keep it, like, 7 days. In your organization, you might keep it 30 days on maximum, because it's not, like, for every time. It's like a persistent storage I don't prefer, ready.
Krish NAik: Because I know that repeated queries will again come again, like, in… like, when you have, like, 1,000 users, out of that 1,000, in every 3 months, there will be pretty much repetition. So, I always keep on removing them.
Krish NAik: I hope you get that. It means that it, like, it comes in, it comes out. That's why, pretty much in P4-based. First in, first out, a simple implementation based on that, the latest part I keep on implementing it.
Krish NAik: Now, you have to think from user perspective also, because right now it's a generic approach, but when you think from user perspective, then user-level catch also you need to meet.
Krish NAik: Like, for every user in the DB from your Postgres with that user ID, you need to maintain that user-level catcher, so that later on, he or she resumes the conversation, so at least that you can have a summary
Krish NAik: Of that, so that if he or she asks anything with respect to that. That's how OpenAI works, or any Anthropic works, based on your chat test.
Abhishek: Yeah. So, but then, is it, is it fine to embed this, all this in ingestion Python, or rather, we should have it, have caching done in the query,
Krish NAik: People defined pipelines. Like, in my case, document ingestion pipeline was, I was keeping it an SKL.
Krish NAik: Okay, now that RAG that, were your, query and response models for MySQL and for my RAG, that only I'm keeping it.
Krish NAik: And rabies.
Krish NAik: You don't need to keep your document things and write, only that query and response, because that you really need.
Krish NAik: Because in real time, the embedding will come, and really in real time. Because I showed you, if you're not working, the response time 20 seconds as compared to only in millisecond. So that impacts a lot. So the user experience becomes much better.
Krish NAik: Only, you need to save the query and the response.
Abhishek: Okay, so are we going to have these example, like, user-level caching as well?
Krish NAik: User-level catching, the implementation will be the same, you know? Now, that will be based on Postgres. Now, I don't want to build a productive thing that for every user in the database, based on that ID, you have to keep it as simple.
Abhishek: Tensioner.
Krish NAik: Yes. Like, for a user, you keep it for every session, whichever the sessions. Based on that, you can create a summary also, so that later on, if something he or she is asking, you can pick it from the chat summary, and that way we create it.
Krish NAik: Then later on, after the course, we can discuss a little bit about that.
Abhishek: Thank you, thanks.
Krish NAik: Oh, great.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Hey, hi, Paul. Deva Desai, thanks for the session. So, two questions. One, actually, the Abhishek already, take over. That was my question also, but I have one slight additional thing.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Suppose the user level, stops, or maybe for the whatever queries, or maybe the outputs are coming, or like the way we are doing in the chat GPT or somewhere, that the…
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: So, so those things, if we have to store it in the PGVector, and latter point, do I need to… if I log into the app, do I need to load it from PGVector to Redis, and then my conversation will start?
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, no, no, no, no. Directly from PGVector. Again, why will bring it to Redix?
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay, so PGVector has that capability, kind of?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes. Jenny, any type of short-term memory, long-term memory, somewhere SQLite is used, okay? So, everywhere, like, SQLite or some variant of SQLite, you can always use it.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay, okay. Thank you so much. And one other thing, out of this context, actually, you have shown us very nice, pictorial diagram, which you have embedded into the Markdown file, actually, the read.md file, right? The overall kind of, graphs that how the flow is running, right? Is it something you created manually, or it was…
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: No, no, no, no, directly. Like, I write a prompt, create a mermaid workflow.
Krish NAik: Like, once I complete the deployment, instantly I write it. Okay, like, my deployment is successful, then only I tell it, okay, generate a mermaid workflow, and keep it in a renderable, like a markdown file.
Krish NAik: So that I can.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Okay. And for that, what input I have to give to… that's a prompting? I mean, you use some inbuilt.
Krish NAik: Yes. Yes, I use LLMs, so generally, like, ChatGPT, JLM, these, or Claude. So there, I pass it, like, create a mermaid workflow. Now, this is a mermaid code. If you look into the original file, you'll be having that three, like, within a code, the entire mermaid workflow.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Got it, got it.
DEBAJYOTI MUKHOPADHYAY: Dan, thank you so much.
Rahul Parihar: Hey, Paul,
Rahul Parihar: So, I did a sync with the latest codebase, and I wanted to share the screen, and I'm not sure what's going on.
Krish NAik: No, no, no, no, no, latest codebase, not… it will not work in one shot. Lambda update and other things are there.
Rahul Parihar: No, no, not the Lambda one, I'm talking about the local, you know, just the local one.
Krish NAik: The only one that should work.
Krish NAik: Local one, even I'm not yesterday, I've only worked on the cloud part, because yesterday I showed you the local one as well.
Krish NAik: Because that part even I've not done any local testing, but I think it should work.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, till yesterday, this was working, so I'm just surprised what has changed between yesterday and today. So, I have my…
Rahul Parihar: I have my services been false. They were all true yesterday, and you can see it is working on local, as well as… it was working on my S3, you know?
Rahul Parihar: But today, I just… reclone, I just…
Rahul Parihar: Restarted? I think so. What's going on here?
Krish NAik: is I just wait, I think, because really, like, yesterday night only, I did it local, but I think it should work. So, we can give it a little bit more.
E2317: dot PY.
Krish NAik: No, no.
E2317: main.py.
E2317: In New York.
Krish NAik: Those three lines of code have you commented?
Krish NAik: Yesterday, I told, there is a comment in…
E2317: startup event, I think he has.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, yes, I think he has.
E2317: actually, so you…
Krish NAik: heard that.
E2317: If you go there?
Krish NAik: Main dot UI.
E2317: Go app?
Krish NAik: field.
Krish NAik: app folder main.
Rahul Parihar: Paul.
Krish NAik: open the entry point, main.py, main.
E2317: admin.py. Go up.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, okay, sorry, sorry, sorry, okay.
Krish NAik: Go to the last ending of the file.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Ending on 35.
Krish NAik: In Lambda, you don't need to initialize the service, that's why, yes. Go above. There, comments are written, you have to.
E2317: Just like startup, yes, huh?
Krish NAik: Yes, these three.
E2317: 1379.
Krish NAik: Yes.
E2317: 1382. 137921382.
Krish NAik: this…
Rahul Parihar: 1 and 2.
Krish NAik: 2, 3, 4 lines. Four lines, just remove it.
E2317: 137921382.
Rahul Parihar: Oh…
Krish NAik: In Lambda, you don't need an initialization directly.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, good.
E2317: Because initialized service here, because it is trying to check all the… I think, sorry, in one of the… in health, health fast API route, right? You have, initialized if all the services are null, then only it is writing as degraded as… is healthy.
E2317: I think it is not calling that surface.
Krish NAik: Yes, it was not falling, that's why.
Rahul Parihar: Oh, okay, okay.
Krish NAik: For Lambda deployment, you don't need this, so that's why generally, for Lambda deployment, I keep it commented.
Rahul Parihar: Got it. Got it.
Rahul Parihar: Let me just try that, and we'll connect back.
Rahul Parihar: Thanks. And one more, one more… I'll, I'll drop you an email. There, there was… there was a…
Rahul Parihar: The IIT Rootkey has launched a AI program. Have you heard about it? Is it, like, matured enough?
Krish NAik: Hold on.
Rahul Parihar: No, no.
Krish NAik: IIT rookie, tell me exactly. I need to look into the curriculum.
Krish NAik: Because college curriculums are pretty much outdated that I feel.
Rahul Parihar: Don't get it.
Krish NAik: majorly all colleges, whether it's US or other… if it's not based on R&D, the main curriculum, it's pretty much outdated. Major in every Indian colleges, or in U.S. anywhere. I feel that, at least with respect to much more recent implementations.
Krish NAik: like, Chinese universities are much more better. Chinese, Hong Kong, Singapore.
Rahul Parihar: Otherwise…
Krish NAik: world is pretty much, they use something like 2-3 years backup content.
Rahul Parihar: But they are… they are teaching, like, shipping of the, running AI apps, multimodel, LLM ops, quality. So I just shared you the link, Paul, could you have a look onto the…
Krish NAik: This is from Masai School, no? Another…
Rahul Parihar: tell you.
Krish NAik: Oh…
Rahul Parihar: I don't know anything about it, they just had an entrance, and I kind of cleared.
Krish NAik: It totally depends, first of all. Like, just… let me just open this one.
Krish NAik: Where is the curriculum?
Rahul Parihar: Go at the very bottom.
Rahul Parihar: Yeah, existed.
Krish NAik: This is, okay, now… this is…
Krish NAik: for you, JavaScript is not required. You are a backend guy, if you really… Python, again, waste of time. Back-end engineering, starting 3 modules, waste of time. Module 4, waste of time. See, you guys are in pretty much advanced state. That's why now this, quoting agents, workflow, context engineering.
Krish NAik: These things, coding agents in this course, Langraph, I'll be talking about, and really, like, modulesing for deploying FastAPI applications, remove it, actually, see.
Krish NAik: When you actually move to multimodal, no. Then, these type of inferencing through Fast API, we need better inferences. I'm just showing you, like, we work with VLLM, okay? Now, this is one package that we work with. Like, these are cheap, fast, easy, cheap LLMs serving for everyone.
Krish NAik: Otherwise, I will go with, SIGLAB.
Krish NAik: Okay? These are actually people that we do use for surveying.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, like, these type of things are much more advanced stuff.
Krish NAik: I don't feel… it totally depends. So, how much they are charging?
Rahul Parihar: I'm not sure. I… I… it was just an IIT one, that's why I thought of, considering… and the…
Krish NAik: If you need a degree, okay, now see, getting a formal degree, it's like an MS or something like that, then it's a different story. But if it's a diploma-based program, then really, like.
Rahul Parihar: It's a certificate.
Krish NAik: Okay, 50,000 plus GST, 18% add on top of that. Okay, really, like, really…
Krish NAik: Don't go through that. Just wait for a few months, okay? Because the same thing, but much more advanced things that I am planning.
Krish NAik: Okay. That's why, okay. Because, see, I feel that in these type of modules, what is the main pain point? Because actually what is being used, really getting that information. Because they will be teaching everything correct, but the level that matters to me.
Krish NAik: From a 4 to 5 years, or a 6 years of guide, if you want to actually do it in your organization, that plays a crucial role.
Krish NAik: Because they are actually game changers.
Krish NAik: See, I have been teaching from 2019, so I know all the major competitors in the market, at least in the Indian market, if you see.
Krish NAik: When I look into their curriculum, I feel that then, because that's why, like, Krish, our mentors are much more developer-centric, rather than teaching just the core concept.
Krish NAik: Okay, like, if I'm talking about Manch, everybody, Sunny, majorly, like, right now, we are bringing the mentors, so first of all.
Krish NAik: Before bringing the mentors, I always check out whether they can teach that or not. Even mentor hiring is a very big problem.
Krish NAik: plan, because the way that I feel… most of the mentors feel overwhelmed to teach these things. If somebody is really, like, comfortable, then only we do hire. In our case, it's different. So, don't wait right now. Multimodality.
Krish NAik: In this course, you have the multimodal rack. There, I'll be talking about a few things, but for multimodality, you need good info.
Krish NAik: Again, like, for this course, rather than that course money.
Krish NAik: There are so many open source available content. If you spend that 50K on infra, I feel that your learning will be much more better, rather than on the content.
Krish NAik: That's my thinking always, because I prefer that, okay, I need to, if I'm spending some money, I will spend it on IMFRA much more, because most of the things are available. If you try to collate, if you sit for a few hours, like, the research takes a really lot of time to collate down every material in one place.
Krish NAik: But if you haven't done it, I know most of the things are available.
Krish NAik: Generally, for, VLLM, I think, I'm telling you, if you are actually focusing on, Merck no one, okay? The…
Krish NAik: what arena, because I follow her, she's writing the book on O'Reilly, Hmm… Marof… In ERV move.
Krish NAik: hugging fields. I follow her. She's, like, my me, Mobuan, yes. This is a girl, like, shh, really, like, awesome.
Krish NAik: She's. So, I follow her, like, she's writing the book. Now, the book is not completed, but, like, I follow, this exactly. You can look into what are the things that comes.
Krish NAik: she… it's only for visual computing. Yeah, like, only computer vision. Okay, like, all the things that she posts, whether in LinkedIn, whether in Twitter, very much related to multimodality, rather than only unimodal stuff.
Krish NAik: So, like, I follow people, so really, like, getting the content is not…
Krish NAik: Like, it's easier. So I'm planning for these type of sessions, but yes.
Krish NAik: once my audience can ingest that. That is the main thing.
Krish NAik: Every audience cannot do that particular ingestion.
Krish NAik: Okay, that's right.
Rahul Parihar: said that this is going to be more theoretical, right? Not the practical way, the way we are… the way you are…
Krish NAik: Yes. Yes, it's like practical implementation law, because really the practicals are tough here. It means that, when you're actually setting up infra and other things, rather than going for a hosted web solution, like, for that course, because I feel if I'm teaching you VLMs, you need to at least spend $50.
Krish NAik: Okay, and if you are going with any hosted service, I feel that if you have a GPU in your local for, like, a 5090, at least the requirement is 24GB of VRAN. That should be there in your system.
Krish NAik: That's right. So, don't spend a lot, rather than do research. If you have a very specific requirement, you can tell me, I can tell you that my sources are from
Krish NAik: Okay, because if you ask me, tell me, generic, all what… that generic is not possible for me. Like, I follow for every type of task, there are certain guys and certain people.
Krish NAik: So, when you ask me a specific thing, then I will actually go to that, and then I will tell.
Rahul Parihar: So, Paul, I am associated to a couple of startups, you know, and I'm kind of building products, so I have few…
Rahul Parihar: technical, you know, guidance or advisory services that are required, specifically on the coding platforms, you know? Like,
Rahul Parihar: for example, generative AI, EdTech-based product is there. Another is…
Rahul Parihar: So, I wanted specific support on the technical ground, whether it's an architectural, whether it's an implementation, or whether it's an POC to production deployment kind of a consulting. What is the offering? Do you think, Chris, or you would be interested?
Krish NAik: Honestly, we don't have the time, that is the main problem. See, like, yeah, for this course also, when I'm creating a certain content, okay, because I feel that this is a pilot batch. In pilot batch, we need to work more harder, as compared to, I know, in RAG 2.0, I don't have to work so much hard.
Krish NAik: So that's why I will take another struggle, which is that the advanced track. It means that, see, I keep on my learning, but I do a lot of things. But my level, I know that generally, if I hire a guy, it takes me at least more than one year. It means that I sit with him at nights, I have to train that guy.
Krish NAik: Then, in that way. Like, Sunny, I have hired Sonny, like, back in 2020, I trained him. Many guys, like, Boppy is also there, I hired him. Like, training guys is really the toughest thing, because I got a CTO who actually sat with me, and, like, for 2 years, he taught me everything.
Krish NAik: And he was a Java background, like, really, with respect to products, he was an Apple product manager. So, like, I learned a lot of things from him, then actually, with respect to R&D and research, it becomes a little bit different. Because my job is not to productionize, I'm much more focused on R&D, that's why I don't work with agents or that.
Krish NAik: My job is the one way, if you are doing something, how to do it in 10 different ways. Out of that, let's do the R&D, then finally the… it goes to the dev team to take that final decision. So I take the decision that this should be your implementation.
Krish NAik: Okay, so once my R&D team completes that research.
Krish NAik: then that's the production guys I know, because in the market, to productionize the stuff, it's…
Krish NAik: there will be many, many guys. But to do the R&D, that's the pain point, because I feel there are very, very laser guys in the market who actually does that.
Rahul Parihar: Got it. Okay.
shrey: Hi, boy.
Rahul Parihar: Come on.
shrey: Actually, I wanted to ask something regarding the last, in our session. So, I was just going through…
shrey: That, that multi… multi-data rack project, and I'm basically…
Krish NAik: My data and this project is exactly the same. In that one, actually, I was doing some testing, that's why the code is exactly the same. Okay, few things only, I think the catching feature
Krish NAik: like, implementation, that S3 integration, I brought it here. So, it's the same piece of goods.
Krish NAik: From multidata that I have brought it here. Just created a new one.
shrey: Yes, yes. So, I was actually implementing it yesterday, because I missed the class that
shrey: So I was just, trying to run it, but I'm facing some issues. Will it be okay if I just share my screen for a minute?
Krish NAik: Yes, you can share it. Okay, in the meantime, somebody else, I will add, Share to the panelist.
Krish NAik: Okay, how does whip pain, Rajat… okay, then comes… Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Hi, Paul.
Krish NAik: Yes.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, Paul, last week I have given one interview, and in that interview, so thank you for your deep understanding, like, I was able to answer all the questions relating to the coding part and the things that you have teached.
Rajat Khanna: But the person was also asking about how all these things can be done only on the AWS environment.
Rajat Khanna: Like, how the AWS architecture comes…
Rajat Khanna: how each solution, cost estimation, and all those things can be done only on the AWS part. So, after some search, like, I come to know the models and how the pipeline and everything will work, so diagrams comes into play. He want to… he asked me to explain the AWS-related architecture and all.
Krish NAik: Alright.
Rajat Khanna: to study that as well?
Krish NAik: See, like, like, I… last time, like, Muthosa and a few people told us they will be going for that AWS certification. If you want, I can create a problem statement with a list of services.
Krish NAik: Because I know in this batch, few people are at least good in AWS, like, Motaza is really good. Okay, like, a few people I know. Okay, because the list of services I will provide you, those 20 services per rack, because therefore, parsing, you'll be using the AI services, everything from AI.
Krish NAik: For triggers, you will be using bridge events, the list of services, I already have that document, but I thought about, after Project 3, I will be sharing that. If you need that, drop me a mail, I will share that document, the complete list with that.
Rajat Khanna: Okay, what's the person name, if I can connect with who is building this AWS?
Krish NAik: Senior batch, I know Martha, because he's from older batches, and, like, he's also in senior architect level, so I know that he's understanding with respect to his really good, that's why.
Krish NAik: Okay, you can connect with them. Also, share your LinkedIn, I think you were there in the meeting. If you want, you can connect. Because very few people, I know other two people are there, but again, I forget their names, because they continuously see every class they go to it.
Krish NAik: Okay, so, in chat, I will put you, okay, and then in chat, you can get it. Just wait, Rachat.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Krish NAik: Because after Project 3, I will ask you, like, set up your own team, connect, at least. The main thing is networking is also important.
Krish NAik: Because right now, due to security, the main problem is if I start creating WhatsApp group, no. Like, I know in future it becomes a problem.
Krish NAik: Generally. Like, professional signs generally are seen with fresh air.
Krish NAik: the main problem. That's why very less, I don't deal with facial balloon.
Krish NAik: or freshly develops much harder. So, Rajat, if you can directly type in the chat who's two panelists, I think you can see the message of Murd Gaza.
Rajat Khanna: No, I went…
Krish NAik: is here, and panelists will adjust to it. Copy, please, copy.
Krish NAik: few people.
Krish NAik: Most clear sci-fi.
Krish NAik: Yes. Just click on that and then connect with them.
Krish NAik: He is there in the columns.
Rajat Khanna: Okay.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, thank you. Thank you.
shrey: Also, actually, I'm trying to start this, near I…
Krish NAik: Whoopi.
shrey: I get an error that, you know, there's some issues…
Krish NAik: I didn't take validation error, so probably just check your ENV file with your config file. If something extra is there, because in config file, we might add that ignore extra, that particular parameter, because of that. Yesterday, I think somebody else was also getting that particular issue.
Krish NAik: I think who was, like, whipping over there, or somebody else, I think.
Krish NAik: I think, Vipin, and you're studying the invitation? Yes.
Vipin Tiwari: Yes, yes, I also got some resources here.
Krish NAik: Did you resolve it?
Vipin Tiwari: Not yet.
Krish NAik: So, just check in the error exactly for which configuration it's getting. So, provide…
shrey: I actually checked, I am not able to find… I mean, I was just going for the logs.
shrey: I'm.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, I see. Just post the user, host, port, I think, because of that. Please check and remove it from me, if you have that. I think, because of that, it might create the issue.
shrey: It is… it is due to extra values that are there.
shrey: Is that what you're saying?
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, there's line number 68, 69, 70, 71, comment all these things.
shrey: Oh, okay.
Krish NAik: Search, always search. These are very basic Python-level issues, that's why. This is nothing related to AI-related issues, that's why.
shrey: I, I, I know that. I was, feeling.
Krish NAik: do a little bit of chat GPT then also, okay? Just try it out.
Krish NAik: The main thing, see, for this course, you need to spend… if I spent 5 hours to 6 hours teaching, I know that my expectation is you guys spend at least 5 to 6 hours.
Krish NAik: then only, like, you will be in a good state. Otherwise, you will know, but later on, if you try to do any implementation, it becomes much more harder.
shrey: Yeah, I got to…
Krish NAik: AWS resources, alright, you can drop me a mail, Rajat will also drop.
Krish NAik: So, after Project 3, I will be asking you to form a group of, like, 10 or 12 people, and then you can actually plan in the same, like, architect level, 3-4 guys, and then get developers from the team. So, a single team, work on your project, at least. I feel for interview perspective, it's better.
Rajat Khanna: A poll that… that is important thing to learn?
Krish NAik: Yes, cloud-specific, because every organization is using cloud, so they might be sticking to Azure, or GCP, or solutions. It depends, generally, startups can work, but majorly enterprise, they are sticking to a single cloud.
Krish NAik: Because the, LLM cost becomes much more cheaper when you have a contract with AWS for 10 years.
Krish NAik: the same API call from… if I take an example of 10 rupees, I know that same API call, price can be close to 30 pesa. So, pretty much, like, 70% to 60% discount in long-term prospect that you get. So, that's why enterprise…
Krish NAik: As everybody there is sticking to one cloud, whether Azure or AWS, who are the main market leaders. GCP IP, it's lesser, at least, in…
Rajat Khanna: And what about that diagram?
Krish NAik: Take on those also.
Krish NAik: Check the same configuration in main.
Krish NAik: Databricks? Databricks, but again, not every organization is using it.
Krish NAik: It's not like every. Yes, people are there, working on, you know, a few people in Sony, they are in some database, but again, not every. But AWS Azure, it's pretty much common. You have to be good in one cloud. That's why I say, one cloud, you have to be very much good.
Vipin Tiwari: Hey, Paul, beep in this side. I have, only two questions. One is this batch, right, next week, which is starting, right? So, I'm having almost 14 years' experience. Will it help me?
Vipin Tiwari: To learn in all these projects?
Krish NAik: First of all, look the decision. I'm… I'm not the vehicle to take the decision. Look into.
Vipin Tiwari: Okay.
Krish NAik: the project… If you feel like it is a record, then liquid.
Krish NAik: Because otherwise, I know, like, when I share Udemy courses, everybody get it, but nobody looks at it, very few people. Because until we get the stats. Out in this old world, I think we are close to more than 2 lakh learners, and only the completion rate is less than 1%.
Krish NAik: That's why, the completion ratio. So generally, the course, and generally for recordings, that is the main problem. Even I don't love to go through the recordings.
Vipin Tiwari: Yes.
Krish NAik: Generally, I… if I… even for blog posts, if I see… generally, I love podcasts much more, so… but video-based…
Krish NAik: courses, I noted, the same thing that is, we have to look into the documentation.
Vipin Tiwari: Hmm, agree, I agree.
Krish NAik: use a name service server like DeepWeekbench, okay? That's a better way right now in 2025 and 2026.
Vipin Tiwari: Okay, any LLM Ops batch we are looking in future?
Krish NAik: LLM Ops, see, Sunny may know, LLM Ops comes under Sunny. Okay, now Sunny, that Agent 3 batch, I think LLM Ops, or that agent, whichever that is running, LLM Ops, it will be later, for sure. Because that requirement in AE are only ones that we launch.
Krish NAik: Because trending, I feel, Agents is much more trending. Agents is, like, one more, and then comes the basic level courses, where everybody enrolls, like, Ultimate Data Science is the batch. RAG, again, I know… RAG requirements, again, less people comes. LLM, less comes. Agent, everybody comes.
Krish NAik: Because an agent, I don't know, like, what about agents, like, it's just because of marketing much more.
Vipin Tiwari: He is, he is.
Krish NAik: Agent Tech Research is good, I will say, but again, if you look into the poor research.
Krish NAik: Again, because so, so many frameworks, right now, more than 30, 40 frameworks are there, what to teach, and what not to teach.
Krish NAik: that because…
Rajat Khanna: And, Paul, regarding that agent.
Krish NAik: Email address at Krishna at Abhishek.
Rajat Khanna: So, regarding that agentic, the question that you are answering, so, what is more, in demand as respect to the job?
Krish NAik: course will come in.
Krish NAik: Tell me again, I didn't get you.
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so, yeah, so the question, was, which is more in… into the requirement, as per… as respect to the Indian job market. So, as a Gen AI RAG developer, or a, a GenTech AI, developer, or lead the role?
Krish NAik: a ragged them with…
Krish NAik: But in general.
Krish NAik: Bye.
Krish NAik: StandardTreebranches.com. I'll be looking to also Barag with respect to Jenai, he should be very good.
Krish NAik: MNP, that's the core, understanding. And then agentic framework, at least you should be good in one. If you're good in one, you can easily switch to others. So, if somebody knows Landraf, he or she can switch to others. If you know AutoGen, you can switch to others. That's why. You have to be good in one framework. Learning multiple framework is not a solution.
Krish NAik: No, no, so, a gente KIE… Naga is telling Google why.
Rajat Khanna: Then, yeah, easily.
Krish NAik: GenTech AI?
Rajat Khanna: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Is it?
Rajat Khanna: Yeah, so Agent Kai is different as compared to the RAG. So, in the Agent TKI, so it will be, like, multiple agents doing multiple things, and all those, requirements that comes under it. But as a Gen AI or a RAG developer, it's just a simple, straightforward, you have build a RAG pipeline, it is just training on, the specific data, and then you are asking your questions and getting your…
Krish NAik: If you are having external knowledge bases, then the RAG is perfect, as simple as that.
Krish NAik: external unseen data by the LLM, so RAG is one of the easiest solutions that you can build.
Rajat Khanna: No, I'm aspecting on the job level. So, searching job…
Krish NAik: Top level, you have to know RAC also, you have to know about LLMs also. Okay, and about the ops part also. Agent Tech framework, just learn one agent take framework. Like, in this course, we'll be talking about Langraph. If you're good in Langraph, it's fine.
Rajat Khanna: Only one framework is required.
Rajat Khanna: Thank you.
shrey: So, I think, I've actually removed them, it is actually loaded now.
Krish NAik: sugar check, because again, I can see, just check for this variables, progress, Postgres underscore DB, okay, then.
shrey: Yeah, this is the older, locks.
Krish NAik: Okay, okay, recent one, okay, alright. Now it's working alright.
Krish NAik: Okay, inspector.
shrey: Is this… I mean, I saw the video, it was something else, this is the correct…
Krish NAik: There was the initialization, I think,
Krish NAik: Because, again, that repo, even I forgot in the last week. Just try to open this one, 127.7, just try to open that URL and see what it shows.
shrey: weird.
Krish NAik: Here's yours, that is what you want.
shrey: Yeah, that's what I was…
Krish NAik: Where it is opened, I cannot see, no? I can only see your text picture. Oh, okay.
shrey: Okay, okay, sorry.
Krish NAik: Okay, in the chat, Rahul, okay, send me the mail for EWS. That is only the architecture with respect to RAG. Akel Paul, please, can you help me to share the document as Rajat with respect? Okay, drop me a mail, I will add that.
Krish NAik: Sir, can you please share the mail for… it's not AWS resources, I will just tell you, these are the services, okay, and that architecture part. Alright, that part. You can drop me a mail, APP at the request, you can get it in the Notion homepage.
Krish NAik: Okay.
shrey: Yes, I guess. This is it, right?
Krish NAik: Yes, this is it.
shrey: Okay. Through the outside connections. Got it, got it.
Krish NAik: But don't use that report. Use…
Krish NAik: Saturday and Sunday, like, today and yesterday's discussion was tracking.
shrey: Yes, I was… actually, there was some prerequisites with respect to, database that we needed to create on Supernova.
shrey: So for that reason, I was following up. I had to go through and…
Krish NAik: Like, do that creation, that integration can be done in this one also.
shrey: Totally.
Krish NAik: With the same credentials, you can actually pass it with a session puller.
shrey: And the schema is also the same.
Krish NAik: Yes, yes, exactly, everything is same. If you look into the code files, only, like, I think I've done changes in main.py. Other than the schema is exactly the same, which you have inside your data folder. That SQL file, you can copy-paste it directly in the SQL editor of Supervis.
shrey: Recording.
shrey: Okay.
shrey: Okay, thank you so much.
Krish NAik: Welcome.
Krish NAik: Gee, Roli, any other questions? I think no others out there.
Krish NAik: Alright, fine. So, next week, the remaining 3 services we'll be doing, and in the meantime, people who are… you think that you can do it by yourself, okay, so for them, please look into that, where is my screen to you? Look into the repo. Where is the repo? Just wait.
Krish NAik: In the repo, I've added the document for that. If you want, you can go through that document also.
Krish NAik: I think actions, texture sequel…
Krish NAik: Okay, so… inside talks. So, you have this new deploy.md file.
Krish NAik: People who want… okay, please go through this. So, these are step-by-steps.
Krish NAik: like, all the deployment things, because the same thing that I'll be doing it in class also, in front of you. So if you…
Krish NAik: Okay, Hydra, yes, Hydra from Facebook is really good. Like, I've used it, but every time I don't use Hydra. I know Hydra from Facebook, no? I've used Hydra previously.
Krish NAik: But every time, I don't use it for config.
Krish NAik: Yes, I mean, ITRA is a nice open source project.
Krish NAik: Okay, so this AWS IAM, people who want to go through this, so very similar command that I'll be also executing, you can look into these docs.
Krish NAik: So, I don't think I have shared any credentials, yes, everything is already in variables. So, you can have a look into this, otherwise we'll be discussing this. The same deployment steps with the catcher services that we can do.
Krish NAik: Okay, Murthaza, what you can do? Okay, so in your, codebase, you can share that data. Just then, I will directly look into that.
Krish NAik: Okay, just create a public rep one, later on you can share it.
Krish NAik: Alright, Praveen, Kumar, Kanu, you have raised your hand, Praveen.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Hey, Paul, thank you, thanks for the opportunity. Paul, like, I really wanted to thank you, I do not have really any technical questions.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: So I was working here in USA, so the only thing, like, what I understood is, like, from your course, it really boosted my, you know, confidence. The thing is that I really lost, my job, in layoffs. It's been two months and so.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: From there, I've been trying to get, some job on Earth.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: But I was struggling to, you know, track the interest and all that stuff, but, with your course, it was really helpful, Paul, like, you know, it really boosted my, confidence levels and all that stuff. I would like to thank you, that's it.
Krish NAik: It's fine, no issues in there. I think if you're in English and, like, where? I think Rish will be traveling for that NVIDIA GTC, so I think he will be in San Francisco.
Krish NAik: So Major League last year also, many students met. So, if you're in California or in that region, close to San Francisco, I think he will be coming. So, last year, he spent one day only with the students only.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah, I was following him, like, I saw him, like, he, came once two years. Yeah, hopefully next summer.
Krish NAik: This year also in GTC, because here got the invites, now comes the flight bookings. Okay, that flight bookings last time NVIDIA's done, let's see. Like, NVIDIA India team takes a lot of time to provide the updates.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Best way.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: This is one of the amazing courses, Paul, like, I mean, I've studied in top-tier universities, the thing is that, even they don't… I want you know, like, they don't teach all this stuff, Paul, like, this is gold…
Krish NAik: More organizations are good, like, I prefer CMU.
Krish NAik: UC Berkeley, Stanford, okay, they have good content, but with respect to implementations too.
Krish NAik: They have the implementations, but not directly on the top of the courses. Those implementations can be found in the student's repo. Okay, if somebody actually knows the student's report…
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: It's loose.
Krish NAik: you can get, that is a little bit much more research, because I generally follow a few students from few cohorts of Stanford, like CS231, and few courses are there that I do follow everywhere. So from there, I feel that the implementations are good, but that takes time.
Krish NAik: To get a repo of them, and usually they also keep it as public repo.
Krish NAik: But, yes, really for… it takes time, because my entire journey of deep learning started with Stanford courses only.
Krish NAik: Because back in 2015 and 16, there were no courses in India with respect to deep learning. That's right.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Most of my seniors, they were from, Indian… from India, like, they are from ISBs, IADs, I mean, they're into pure statistics and all this stuff.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: If I speak to them, I mean, sometimes they don't… I mean, I won't say they don't know the stuff, but they're not to the level of, you know, you guys provide the services and all that, right? This is top notch, like…
Krish NAik: Everybody in India, like, when I try to find a guy, it takes very time, because I find very similar persons, like, in Bangalore, in ISU Bangalore, there are people
Krish NAik: who are… because in 2019, like, the… who taught me visual computing, that guy is from IEC.
Krish NAik: So I know, like, like, now he has a group of students who actually, like, so I'm connected with the students, so with respect to research, I'm always updated from that community, and few other communities are there.
Krish NAik: So, in India, the community is very, very small, and it's majorly… I won't tell about the ITs, really, I have no idea, but I feel like I see Bangalore is…
Krish NAik: only the one with the utmost level that I feel, with respect to research, from visual computing perspective, or from a natural language perspective.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah.
Krish NAik: Okay.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah, hopefully, like, even… I mean, I just have one normal question, like, are we, concluding these, these sections? Like, I mean, I was… I lost few of the sections in between, and trying to catch up with the classes,
Krish NAik: Watch the videos in 2x, that's the main thing. Watch the videos in 2x, then it will be fine.
Krish NAik: Nobody can sit for 3 hours to watch a session, try to complete it in, like, 1 hour max, because I even know my focus strength is, like, 1 hour. Then again, I wake up. So try to watch the videos in high speed if you miss something.
Krish NAik: And if you miss something, rather than going through the lecture, go through the notebooks. At least I know in few notebooks, directly the code is there, the comments are there in markdown format, it's much faster than going through the lecture, that's fine.
Praveen Kumar Kanuri: Yeah, I'll do.
Krish NAik: Okay, alright guys, so, fine, let's, meet next week, Saturday and, I think, Saturday and Sunday, this project deployment will take time. Okay, so after that, next week, I will start with the project of, hybrid rack. I'm planning with hybrid rack what to put.
Krish NAik: Like, I'm planning for CRAG, corrective rack, a self-healing architecture, something like that. But let's see, because the content this week I won't be creating, probably next week when I do it. Okay, so that will be next to next week's agenda. Next week, this project discussion and their deployment, next to next week, it will be the project 3 starting.
Krish NAik: Alright guys, so, web everyone, thanks for joining.